Wayne: Okay, now introduce Gir.
Gir: I go—I usually go last, but… I’m
Gir.
Trog, laughing: We don’t even remember the
order.
[Baaulp laughs]
Baaulp: I’m Baaulp.
Log: And they call me Log, the Devil’s Mystery.
Wayne: The—the final member.
Baaulp: The Devil’s Mystery…
Wayne: Welcome, it’s another-it’s another
fantastic episode of the Where Do We Begin
podcast, and uh, tonight we have all kinds
of topics and merriment and mirth to share
with you. Uh, it has been three months since
our last episode, since our last episode was
both recorded and released. It’s been a
long time, we got a lot to talk about!
Log: It’s been like a little summer time
capsule.
Wayne: The review it is-it is—this is the
episode of the summer. We’re gonna talk
all about the—
Trog: Mhmm.
Baaulp: Yeah.
Wayne: —We’re gonna talk about the sun,
we’re gonna talk all
about the beach that we didn’t go to.
Trog: It is literally the episode of the summer.
There will not be another episode of this
podcast recorded in summer of 2020.
Wayne: [Laughs] I mean, summer-summer goes—summer
goes into September. So like, if we do an
early September episode…
Trog: Oh, maybe. Yeah.
Wayne: Y’know, that’s fucked up. Summer
should end when September starts. I think-I
think it’s dumb that seasons go into months
that are not attributed to those seasons.
Baaulp: [Crosstalk] What? What? What are you—what?
Wayne: September is the fall to me. Like,
as soon as it’s early September, that’s
fall.
Log: August is fall, practically. Like—
Wayne: Really? No, August is summer! August
is the hottest month.
Log: June and July are summer months and that’s
all I know.
Gir: Yeah, you’re out of your mind.
Log: May, June, July, that sounds like summer.
August—August sounds like tree leaves turning
orange and red.
Wayne: That’s wild, what? Wha—wha—
Gir: You’re wrong. I mean, you’re wrong.
Trog: That’s literally incorrect.
Log: It sounds that—like that don’t-don’t
it?
Wayne: [Crosstalk] It’s not! No! That’s
September!
Gir: [Crosstalk] No, it doesn’t sound like
that!
Log: Think about-think about the words and
how they feel.
Wayne: That’s when—that’s when—that’s
when the -bers start. When the-when the -bers
start, that’s when the leaves come down.
That’s-that’s September, October, November.
Gir: The word August does not convey win—uh,
fall to me.
Log: Indiana was like that in August. I’m…
[unintelligible]
Wayne: August sounds like hot. August sounds
like hot and heat and ice cream and—and
waves.
Gir: It sounds like, “Ah gosh, it’s hot
outside.”
Log: August sounds cold—the word August
sounds colder than many other months.
Trog: You know, I kind of agree.
Wayne: The fuck are you talk—you’re crazy!
Trog: As somebody who lives in Texas where
it’s like a hundred degrees every fucking
day during this month, I would be down with
summer just kind of being the beginning of
June and that’s it. And it just goes away.
[Wayne laughs]
Trog: It’s just really hot, it’s like
nineties for a couple weeks then it goes back
down.
Gir: Oh, cry me a fucking river, I’m sitting
over here with my fuckin’ hundred and thirteen
degrees when I step outside. Choke to death
as soon as I step out the door.
Wayne: Just bring a—just bring a wet towel
and douse yourself.
Baaulp: You can’t blame us for all the sin
making Vegas hot.
[Wayne makes a smug sound of approval]
Trog: Yeah, get further away from Hell.
Gir: There’s so much less sin here than
there usually is, though.
Baaulp: Yeah. Yeah, it’s hot because you’re
closer to Hell ‘cause all the sin, and the
debauchery.
Wayne: Gir, I promise you that once you start
being a good boy and you stop all that sinnin’,
it’ll cool down.
Gir: [Crosstalk] I am good! I’ve never done
anything
wrong.
Wayne: The Devil—the Devil’s gaze—the
Devil’s gaze will go elsewhere and it’ll
cool down.
Log: The magnifying glass will turn away.
[Wayne and Baaulp laugh]
Wayne: [Laughs harder] Imagine God holding
an—Imagine God holding a magnifying glass
up to you specifically. Like he’s just trying
to burn you.
[Trog laughs]
Baaulp: Like he’s burning an ant?
Trog: Yeah.
Wayne: Yeah.
Trog: Just you, specifically.
Gir: That reminds me of, uh—
Wayne: [Crosstalk] Die MasterGir.
Gir: Of uh, I don’t know why, but out of
nowhere I was like, “I’m going to look
up who’s been struck by lightning more than
anyone else on Earth.” And there’s the—there’s
the guy who was like a park ranger who got
struck by lightning seven times.
[Trog laughs]
Trog: And lived?
Gir: Yeah.
Wayne: That guy could do a fuckin’ Electric
Wind God Fist.
Log, in a deep voice: You need to let those
animals die.
Gir: After the third time, he started getting
so paranoid that as soon as he heard thunder
he would just like, hide.
Trog: Then how did he—Well he didn’t follow
his own advice; how did he get struck four
more times?
Wayne: Is there science to it? Like, is the
fact that he was struck and survived, did
it like electrocharge his body in a way that
like, attracted more lightning?
Gir: There was science to it in that he was
a park ranger so he was always outside, and
he was a park ranger in Virginia that has
like, a shitload of thunderstorms.
Wayne: I guess.
Baaulp: Damn, I would look for a new job after,
y’know… The second lightning strike [laughs].
Gir: Yeah, this story doesn’t end happily,
unfortunately.
Wayne: There has never been a man that deserves
superpowers more than that guy. Like, come
on, he needs some abilities. Give—Give the
man some abilities!
Gir: It seemed like by the seventh time he
got struck he just kind of didn’t care anymore.
He just—he told the story like, he got struck
by lightning and he turned to go to his car
to fetch the water that puts out his hair
that caught on fire yet again, and uh, he
got struck while he was fishing and noticed
a bear was trying to steal his fish on his
way back to his car, and he ran back and hit
the bear with a—with a branch.
Wayne: Holy shit. This dude’s kind of badass.
Gir: Yeah, he was.
Trog: You think maybe he had some kind of
weird, like, genetic predisposition like—
Wayne: [Crosstalk] Yeah.
Trog: Was he like—
Wayne: [Crosstalk] Some sort of like, natural
electromagnetism that was attracting bolts
of lightning.
Trog: Yeah, he just was a living magnet? Like—
Log: Yeah, your blood is just iron, I don’t
know how it even moves through your body!
[Baaulp laughs]
Trog: Not even a liquid.
Log: That was like a Family Matters episode.
You guys ever watch Family Matters?
Baaulp: What? No?
Trog: Probably like, one episode ever.
Log: There’s an episode where like, I guess
they have like multiple plot points, but one
of them was that Steve Urkel kept getting
struck by lightning, and he figured out it
was because there was too much iron in his
blood, so he ran all of his blood through
a dialysis machine that he built himself.
Trog: That sounds like… a horrific—like
a—like body horror sitcom.
Gir: Sounds like a very easy way to get yourself
killed.
Wayne: Family Matters was fucking crazy. Have
you seen Dark Urkel Tribute?
Trog: That’s—that’s the only thing I’ve
seen of Family Matters, that’s my entire
frame of reference.
[Wayne laughs]
Baaulp: I never watched most Family Matters
but, I did know that it devolved into the
Steve Urkel show.
Wayne: Out of all those sitcoms—it originally
wasn’t the Steve Urkel show, huh? It was
more about Carl Winslow and his family.
Gir: No, he was just like the neighbor or
something.
Wayne: Yeah.
Baaulp: Steve Urkel wasn’t even in the family
of Family Matters. He was their neighbor [laughs].
Trog: Yeah, it was the kind of thing where
it was just a breakaway hit and the exec.
saw it and was like, “We gotta make fucking
Urkel plush dolls and t-shirts and hats and
put him in every episode, they can’t get
enough.” The nineties had Urkel fever.
Wayne: Out of all those sitcoms—out of all
those—out of all
the sitcoms from that era, Family Matters
had the best theme song by far. By far.
Trog: And then—and then Urkel, he became
Sonic.
Log: When you get down to it, though, it’s
like they kind of had to do it. They fucked
up because they didn’t have like, the best
character in the family, and so they just
had to—they had to do it. It’s not like—it’s
not like Fresh Prince y’know, where like,
every character was good, like Family Matters
I feel like it was Carl Winslow and Steve
Urkel. And like, that was the show.
Wayne: Yeah.
Baaulp: See, if that’s the thing, they should
have just made a spin off. Like fuck it, end
the original show, have a spin off. Have a
spin off—have a spin off where it’s five
Urkels, have a spin off where Urkel clones
himself four times, and it’s a house of
Urkels.
[Trog and Wayne laugh]
Wayne: Hey everybody, we’re back! I hope
you enjoyed one thirty seconds of Family Matters
talk, because now we’ve had to restart the
episode uh, we had a little problem, uh, my
recording software crashed. Uh, and we—we
then talked for about twenty minutes, so we
lost a big chunk of discussion. We talked
about Rogue of Legacy 2, we talked about Fall
Guys, we talked about Steve Urkel, it was
really funny, um, and really insightful.
Trog: You’ll never hear it!
Wayne: You’ll never hear it.
Baaulp: Just imagine it!
Log: I was dominating the conversation, right?
I swerved it into Family Matters and started
talking about One Piece. Like, it was—it
was, uh—
Wayne: Hey. Give me some credit. I brought
up Igaram.
Log: It was ten minutes of Logmore precedence,
and we lost it ‘cause Wayne was being a
little snake.
Wayne: I didn’t know what happened!
[Gir laughs]
Wayne: It didn’t—In the program—Okay,
so, to be fair, to be fair and genuine, I
have a strange recording setup where I use
OBS to record my audio because I already have
like, a very good noise gate setup in there,
and normally if OBS crashes it fuckin’ tells
me! This time, nope, it just wasn’t open.
Just wasn’t open. I just looked down and
I saw that the—the little button on my start
bar didn’t have a light under it.
Gir, mockingly: There is no more little button!
Wayne: [Crosstalk] Buh-bye.
Baaulp: Alright. Listen, listen, listen. Don’t
ask any questions, I need—I need fanart
of Nico Robin from One Piece going, [in a
Steve Urkel voice] “Did I do that?”
[Wayne laughs]
Trog: No context given. You just have to trust
us it was really funny at the time.
Gir: You’ll figure it out.
Wayne: One day you'll realize the true nature
of this request.
Log: Yeah, need a Urkle and One Piece kwosh...
Urkle and one piece crossover.
Wayne: It has been quite some time, since
we've recorded a podcast, and a lot of stuff
has happened! We've been playing a lot of
games, the, uh... we've done all kinds of
streams, all kinds of great content for you
guys, but podcast has been getting neglected,
because we've been working so hard on other
stuff. We put together a very fun production
a few weeks ago called AI-adventure Call,
spearheaded by our-- by our fantastic dog
producer, Trog.
Trog: Woo.
Wayne: Thank you Trog, you did an amazing
job.
Trog: Thank you, yeah.
Wayne: I just wanna talk about it a little
bit.
Trog: Nah, I'm into it.
Wayne: Yeah, Trog- Trog had the original idea
to do something along the lines of Adventure
Call from Limmy Show. And, uh, I, and he was
talking about setting something up and doing
it on his stream, but I was like, I tugged
on his shirt and I was like, "Yo, let me,
let me buy a costume, let me play a character."
And then we turned it into a much larger production,
and it became- it was fuckin' huge! It was
awesome.
Trog: In case you don't know what Adventure
Call from Limmy Show is, it is a series of
skits in which Limmy, who is a comedian, who
has a comedy sketch show, or had a comedy
sketch show, dresses up like a fantasy man,
and hosts a call-in program where you must
best a dungeon.
Wayne: Is he like a satyr?
Log: He's like a bard.
Wayne: [Laughs] He kinda looks like a satyr.
Log: He's more of a, just a general bard,
or a minstrel-
Trog: Yeah, he's kinda just like a dude, but,
um so that was the idea. I was, so like I
had, like, we all love those sketches. Those
sketches are great, and um, we also happen
to all really enjoy AI dungeon as a concept.
And I feel like it was just-
Wayne: [Crosstalk] Oh, yeah. It's Trog's game
of the year!
Trog: It was pretty obvious to me to just
be like, “Why don’t we just do that, like,
why don’t we just combine these two funny
ideas into one.” And so, the idea was born.
And then Wayne bought a bunch of dumb bullshit
on Amazon that like, honestly, whenever you
put that costume on, you transformed into
a different human. It was like, scary.
Wayne: [Laughs] It was awesome!
Trog: You didn’t look like you.
Wayne: It was my—it’s my favorite costume
that I’ve put together yet.
Trog: [Crosstalk] I think it’s my favorite
as well.
Wayne: I’ve done a ton of different costumes—I’ve
done a ton of different costumes for like,
little bits here and there, we—there’s
a caveman—like, my fuckin’, my closet—honestly,
I love stocking up on dumb costume items because
my closet is just full of shit. I could put
together like, so many costumes by combining
them, there’s a caveman, there’s the—uh,
there’s not really a vague term to describe
what the Fushigi Freak is.
Trog, laughing: Morpheus.
Wayne: Uh, but, there’s that. There’s
the Morpheus-like—Morpheus-like individual.
There’s, uh, I have—I have face paint
for like a robot costume. I’ve got a morph
suit, I got—I got a knight’s outfit, there’s
a costume in there I can’t tell you about
yet. The, like, all kinds of shit. The—And,
but this costume, I think the number one thing
was like when we had this idea, I think the
first thing, like when we were in the voicecall
that we all marveled at was like, I think
someone said, “Wayne, you should buy chainmail,”
and then it began.
Trog: Yeah.
Wayne: The—the chainmail was the—it was
the centerpiece. It was the—it was like
the main clip that held it all together. Uh,
and then Scorpy found the beautiful five dollar
goatee.
[Baaulp laughs]
Gir: That—that thing I think was the real
centerpiece if—in my opinion.
Wayne: It worked with the chainmail. Those—those
two together is what transformed me.
Gir: The gems on the crown.
[Wayne laughs]
Trog: So to speak.
Log: Yeah, it was really good. Y’know, I—I
forget, I don’t really think about how easily
accessible Limmy is, now. I wonder if that—I
wonder if these clips have like, gotten to
him in any way.
Gir: I highly, highly, highly doubt it.
Trog: I will one hundred percent admit that
it was like, that that—that was not an original
idea, that was two ideas that already existed
that I thought it would be fun to combine.
I—I one hundred percent give the original
credit for that, that inspiration, to those
Limmy show sketches.
Baaulp: I talked to other streamers, and like,
other people who like, are—we’ve set a—I
think we’ve set a trend! I’ve seen people—more
and more people stream AI Dungeon, and—and
like, but they say like—
Wayne: We’re not the only ones. There’s
bigger streamers than us that do it.
Baaulp: Well—
Wayne: But nobody’s doing anything like
AI-dventure Call. That was—
Trog: That’s true. That’s unique. We’re
raising the bar.
Baaulp: I’ve talked to people and they’re
like, “Yeah, at the end of the day, it is
a text adventure. I wonder if we could make
it more exciting.” Hey, we figured it out
[laughs].
Wayne: And we have other ideas that we haven’t
even done yet! The, like, the-the-the-the
thing with—the thing with like, the reason
that while the idea is a hundred percent Limmy’s,
the reason why it’s like, we, like, our
spin on it is like, valid and justified, is
like, with the Adventure Call on Limmy’s
show, those were like, skits. We put on, like,
an actual like, essentially what would have
been an episode of a TV show. Like, it was
like a three hour long thing rather than just
like a showcase of like their really funny
gags. And I don’t mean to downplay Adventure
Call, that shit’s still hilarious.
Trog: No, I mean it’s-it’s completely
different, right? Because the Adventure Call
skits, they are skits, they are written, it
is a script. The AI Dungeon thing, by the
nature of AI Dungeon, it cannot be prewritten,
like, we-we basically went into it with like,
okay, we’re like—all of the contestants
are gonna kind of have like, their own mini-bit
that they’re doing, but there’s—it’s
all improv, like everything we do, basically.
It’s all just improv in the end, so. It’s
different enough that it’s not like we’re
ripping it off. It’s an homage.
Baaulp: The only gag that wasn’t improv
was the tuna.
Gir: Oh, yeah, the tuna.
Trog, laughing: The tuna? Oh—oh, the grand
prize.
Wayne: Like, we were joking about, like, I
think it was supposed to be beans at first,
like, ‘cause—‘cause we’d been watching
like Legends of the Hidden Temple, and Legend—
Trog: Oh, yeah.
Log: Tuna was the prize in Legends of the
Hidden Temple.
Wayne: It was! Legends—Legends of the Hidden
Temple was like, we’d-we’d been—we-we
were watching it at one point occasionally,
and that show, if you lose on that show, which
most kids do, your prize is so fuckin’ sad.
They give you like, a book with a holographic
cover, or like, a can of tuna. Genuinely!
A can of fucking tuna.
Gir: Here’s a backpack! Enjoy!
Wayne: A backpack! Shoes that might—they
have a plastic strap on them instead of Velcro!
Like, it’s just—
[Baaulp laughs]
Wayne: Or you—[Laughs] Did anyone else hear
that?
Baaulp: Wha—what? What was it?
Gir: [Laughs] Yes, I was like, who’s strangling
a cat!?
Wayne: Baaulp you were like, holding in a
laugh, and it—we just heard like [high pitch
inhale sounds].
[Trog and Baaulp laugh]
Baaulp: My laughs can get pretty fucked up.
Wayne: You charge ‘em up.
Baaulp: Wha—what was the—what was the
slogan for the shoes? Like, wasn’t the slogan
like, “Get Ready to Devolve,” or some
shit?
Wayne: Yeah it was like, “Time to Mutate,”
it was, “Time to Mutate!”
[Log and Trog laugh]
Baaulp: Yes! It was, “Time to Mutate!”
What the fuck?
Gir: That’s a terrible slogan.
Log: Typical nineties.
Wayne: It was literally just—it was just
a sneaker for kids with like, a zip tie on
it.
Baaulp, laughing: Yeah.
Wayne: Like, I’m pretty sure it was just
a zip tie. And then the—so, the slogan was
“Time to Mutate,” and the video, the commercial
was like, it was like a stop motion of a kid
standing in like a walking position and just
moving with the stop motion, and—
Baaulp: [Crosstalk] Yeah, and they were like
in an empty warehouse.
Wayne: — I think-I think there was like,
Scorpy—Scorpy said like, “Yeah, if I saw
them when I was a kid, I would think that
like, that was a shoe that—that made it
so you didn’t have to pick up your feet.
Like, you’d just do that.”
[Baaulp laughs]
Gir: I thought it was those like, rollerblade
shoes at first.
Wayne: Yeah, like Heelys!
Gir: Yeah, exactly.
Trog: Yeah. I would say the AI Adventure Call
thing, we were—we were y’know, Limmy’s
show, and just like call-in shows in general—
Wayne: [Crosstalk] Yeah, public access.
Trog: —and then also we’ve just been watching
like, a handful of nineties gameshows at the
time, we-we were like, we were watching Supermarket
Sweep and Legends of the Hidden Temple, and
I think Gack?
Wayne: Did—I didn’t watch Gack.
Trog: I think we watched a couple epi—or
GUTS, that’s what it was, not Gack.
Wayne: In the past we used to—we used to
watch the shows that were more akin to like,
the fantasy type shit, like—like Knightmare.
Trog: Oh, yeah, yeah.
Wayne: Like, which, if you don’t know what
Knightmare is, Knightmare is probably one
of the funniest things to ever air on TV in
earnest, which is like, it’s a show where
kids would like, they would put a bucket on
a kid’s head and make him stand in a room
with a greenscreen while other kids would
guide him through the greenscreen room.
Trog: [Crosstalk] Oh man.
[Baaulp laughs]
Baaulp: Yeah!
Gir: What? I’ve never heard of this show.
Trog: Oh, you didn’t watch those with us?
Log: They put a child in a diving bell and
the other ones have to—have to provide direction
via like, intercom.
Trog: We have to rewatch those. We have to
rewatch those.
Baaulp: It is a very British take on the Nickelodeon
type gameshows for kids where it’s like,
“Okay, we can build an extravagant set,
or, we can just greenscreen everything and
use matte paintings.” “Well, but then
the kid just sees green.” “Well, okay,
well, y’know, maybe we have like, people
in green suits jumping around and we just
tell the kids beforehand that y’know, hey
listen, it’s for the show, you’re only
going to see green, just use your imagination.”
“No, let’s just put a bucket on their
head so they don’t see anything!” Like—[laughs].
Wayne: [Laughs] It’s like—it’s like
literally a bucket. It’s—
Trog: They can’t-they can’t witness it.
Wayne: It’s actually a bucket. It might
have some like paint on it or something to
make it look like a helmet—
Trog: It’s supposed to be a helmet.
Baaulp: Yeah, it’s a bucket! [Laughs]
Wayne: But it’s like—but it’s like—the
kid-the kid can see out the bottom like a
bucket.
Log: It’s just incredibly funny because
like, because of this, because the kid can’t
see anything and it’s all greenscreen, they’re
like, in very dire situations during the show
like-like you walk into—
Baaulp: [Crosstalk] Yeah.
Log: —Like they walk into the wrong room
and their-their like—their skin evaporates
or something and it just shows a little animation
of like, skin going away from a head and leaving
a skull, and the skull explodes.
[Wayne and Baaulp laugh]
Log: It’s like, oh, the kid doesn’t—like
the kid’s just standing there, y’know.
Baaulp, laughing: Yeah!
Log: Like-like, if they-if they lose—If
they lose they’re not even gonna know, they’re
gonna like fall off a pit but they’re just
standing there.
Wayne: And then his guides are like, “Sorry
Jimmy, your face melted.”
[Baaulp laughs]
Trog: Exactly. It’s a combination of like,
the kid with the bucket on his head has no
agency, right? It’s like—
Baaulp: Yeah.
Trog: Okay, it’s the kid with the bucket
on his head and then it’s like their three
friends like, looking at a little CRT monitor
with the computer graphics on it trying to
like, direct them. So, it’s a combination
of the kid with the bucket could be dumb,
and also it’s like, kids trying to give
directions. Like, like little—
Wayne: It’s great.
Trog: Like, small kids. Not like—I would
say probably like, grade school, right? Like,
first through fifth grade.
Wayne: You will have the child-like, the chi—the
only capable in a child error where like,
the guide—the British guide kid will go
like, “Left! Left!” And the kid will just
clearly, obviously step to the right, like—
Trog: Yeah.
Wayne: There’s just like, there’s both-there’s
both an inability to create directions, and
an inability to process them in the correct
way.
Baaulp: It’s been a long while since we
watched that show, but I distinctly remember
this happening a lot, they’d be like, [in
a British accent] “Okay Daniel, you’re-you’re
in a room with—and with a-with lava underneath
and you’ve got to pass this bridge but it’s
not a straight shot so I’ll be guiding you.
Okay, move—step to your right.” “My
right or your right?” [Laughs]
Trog, laughing: “What do you mean?”
Wayne: Yeah, yeah! They could-they could never
translate that difference. Like, it was so
difficult.
Gir: Ah, this is actually starting to sound
familiar. I think, I think I’m like on the
cusp of remembering exactly what we watched.
Baaulp: You definitely watched this with—this
shit with us [laughs].
Trog: We should absolutely rewatch these,
it’s been long enough.
Wayne: Normally when we have ideas, like for
a good thing to put—like, a good production
to put on, we keep it to ourselves, but I’m
gonna say this on the podcast because if-if
this ever happened it would be a long time
from now and most of you will forget, but
I want to just do Knightmare.
Baaulp: You just want to do Knightmare? [Laughs]
Wayne: Like if-if we could—No, no, ‘cause
let’s say—okay, let’s say we all go—let’s
say we all go to Vegas, like, we could just
rent like a giant greenscreen room like Jerma
does, and just do Knightmare. Like, we’d
just have to make the assets.
Trog: That is true.
Wayne: It would be so fucking funny, especially
that concept but with like, our sense of humor
and it being adults, I think would be so good.
Baaulp: Now would it still be fantasy based?
Or would you pick a different setting?
Wayne: I think it has—I think it has to
be.
Baaulp: It has to be fantasy?
Gir: I think that’s to be determined.
Wayne: To be determined. I think—I think
fantasy’s the funniest, though.
Log: I think it should be—I think it should
be Star Trek but you have a bucket on your
head [laughs].
[Wayne, Baaulp, Trog and Gir laugh]
Baaulp: Oh my god that’s so good!
Wayne: “There’s a Romulan ahead, aim your
phaser to the left, no-no-a little-no, to
the right, ah.”
Gir: “To your—no.”
Baaulp: “My left or your left?”
Wayne: Ugh. Ohh.
Trog: That’d be good. Someday.
Log: “You have to reach the engineering
room, it’s not a straight shot, though.”
Wayne: There’s just like, holes in the floor,
like it’s the Star Trek Enterprise but there’s
just—
[Baaulp laughs]
Wayne: —like, that’s the kind of obstacles
that the kids in Knightmare had to face! It
wasn’t just like, there’s like a trap
you need to—you need to like disarm it,
or you need to like move past this goblin,
it would literally be like, they’d have
to walk along a narrow bridge, and if they
walked too far to the left they would just
like drop the greenscreen footage, they would
just pan it downwards so it looked like the
kid fell, like—
Baaulp: “Alright Trog, uh, you’re at Ten
Forward, Guinan wants to talk to you, okay?”
[Wayne laughs]
Baaulp: “Alright, take a step forward, okay,
you’re not a-you’re—no, you’re not
at the bar yet—"
Wayne: “You walked in the Holodeck.”
[Trog laughs]
Log: “The Enterprise is-is going to Starbase
74 for maintenance, there are holes in the
ground of [unintelligible].”
[Baaulp and Wayne laugh]
Wayne: Yeah, I think taking-taking the concepts
that are present in Knightmare, like just
random holes in the ground, and putting them
in a place where they shouldn’t be is a
great idea.
Gir: “Ah, sorry buddy, you clipped through
the floor, there was a space anomaly you didn’t
see.”
[Wayne laughs]
Baaulp: “There’s a room with three Klingons
and they’re like, really angry. Okay, you’re
gonna have to fight ‘em. Oh, dodge right!
Dodge right-dodge right! Oh, well, you got
stabbed.”
Wayne: “Watch out it’s the Borg, he’s
shooting at you!”
Trog: I could have sworn that there was like,
s—I could be misremembering this, because
it’s been a long time since we’ve watched
this, but I could have sworn there was like
a-a room, that had like, like something rotating
in the middle that they had to jump over,
but it’s not real. Like, it’s like—
Baaulp: Yes!
Wayne: I do remember that.
Trog: —They just had to tell them, “Okay,
jump now.” And it’s like, this seems impossible.
Like yeah, ok, maybe the kids aren’t the
best at giving directions, but this gameshow
is like, rigged as well.
Wayne: I remember is-isn’t there—I remember
there’s like a talking wall that like, they-they
would like walk into a room and there’d
be like a talking wall and it would like ask
a riddle and if you just got it wrong three
times he just killed you.
[Baaulp laughs]
Gir: Everyone’s got that wall in their house.
Baaulp: Like nineties British television for
kids ranged from like insane to kind of awesome.
I remember there’d be just like a lot of
shows about video games. And not like-not
like the way G4 was, it was just like, “Oh
yeah, it’d be dope if we just had a Mortal
Kombat tournament and just invited all these
kids—”
Log: [Crosstalk] And you had to fight Baraka.
Baaulp: Yeah, you have to fight Baraka [laughs].
Like, that’s dope! Like, okay!
Log: Man, oh man. Y’know, there was video
game talk in the uh, the dead recording that—
Trog: [Crosstalk] The lost episode.
Log: —of a bygone era, that the lost episode
there was video game talk—There was a lot
of talk about Fall Gay—Fall—
[Wayne, Baaulp, Gir, and Trog laugh]
Trog: Oh, noooo.
Wayne: Lot of talk about them Fall Gays.
Log: Yeah, there was a lot of talk about Fall
Guys, um, we’re not gonna talk about that.
Fuck that. Um, I’ll talk about a game I
played, okay?
Gir: Okay.
[A beat of silence before Log laughs a little]
Gir: Take the reins.
Log: Do I—Do I have permission?
Trog: Yeah.
Log: Okay. Hylics 2 came out a while ago.
Baaulp: Ohhhhh.
Log: And I-I started playing it whenever it
came out, and I like, stopped because it didn’t
have controller support. It had like, half
of a controller support. You could use the
D-pad and that was it. Um, but then recently
they added controller support to it so I started
playing it, I started playing it on stream.
That’s a good ole game, I gotta say.
Baaulp: Nice! Yeah, it looks cool!
Log: It’s-it’s weird ‘cause the first
Hylics game, like, nothing made sense. Every
NPC spoke in randomly generated dialogue um—
Wayne: Yeah, does Hylics 2 still have the
randomly generated bullshit? Like, I liked
it.
Log: Nah-no, the-the—Every NPC still like,
talks in bullshit but it’s like, written
bullshit instead of procedurally generated.
Gir: Meaningful bullshit.
Log: Like the—You’ll-you’ll meet a party
member and he says, “I’m looking—I’m-I’m
at this beach looking for a cabinet.” Um,
but he-but he’ll always say that. Um, so
it’s good, uh, it’s a turn-based RPG,
the RPG part is pretty hard, um, I thought
the first boss—There’s just like a whole
bunch of shit that I didn’t expect. Like,
I was just walking around and I clicked-I
like clicked on a thing and it took me into
a 2D platformer section—
Wayne: Yeah. That was in the trailers.
Log: It’s like-it’s like fuckin’ uh,
it was like Mario and Luigi y’know, Superstar
Saga they had those little things.
Wayne: Mhmm.
Log: It’s like that. Yeah, like, there’s
like alternate ways to like solve the problems
in areas, surprising. And they started talking
about a gibbylet.
Gir: Yeah.
Wayne: What?
Log: Yeah.
Trog: What’s that?
Log: It’s uh, it’s a piece of a gibby.
Trog: Oh.
Gir: Sure, man.
Log: I don’t know, I was just-I was just
pleased to read gibbylet because we s—we
always talk about joglets and troglets and
here’s a game where now I have to like go
out and find a gibbylet and kill it.
[Wayne and Baaulp laugh]
Baaulp: So it—so it-so it’s nice to know
Mason Lindroth has the same—is on the same
wavelength as us, is [what] you’re saying?
Log: Yeah.
Gir: I mean, the main character’s name is
Wayne.
Baaulp: Ooohhhh.
Wayne: Yeah that’s uh, that’s not a coincidence.
It’s not a coincidence, it’s fully intentional.
Gir: One hundred percent.
Trog: It’s not a coincidence because the
person thought of that and chose it. It wasn’t
pick—It wasn’t determined at complete
random.
Gir: They didn’t write the name down and
look down and go, “Oh, that’s a good name!”
Wayne: I played Hylics 1 for a bit, but like,
that game was har—kind of impenetrable,
like—It was—I just had no clue what I
was fucking doing and I think I died really
early on and it just like—never touched
it again.
Log: Oh, yeah. It’s—Hylics 1 and 2 are
like Dungeons and Dragons in that action economy
is everything.
Wayne: Yeah.
Log: Um, Hylics 2 is a lot better in that
it gives you uh, two of your party members
very early on.
Wayne: Mhmm.
Log: Um, in Hylics 1 you’re just kind of
stuck as just Wayne for a long time and you
get your ass beat by everything.
Wayne: [Laughs] It’s-It’s—It was hard
as fuck. Um, but yeah, visually that game
was one of a kind and very, very cool, as
well. I should maybe check out Hylics 2.
Trog: Talking about weird, like, abstract
video games, I played Anodyne 1 and 2 uh,
recently. Both games are really good. I would
highly recommend those to anybody who likes
uh, weird, heady, confusing narrative based
video games with a little bit of puzzles thrown
in.
Log: That game is really funny looking, it
looks like the Nickelodeon Movie Maker.
Trog: A little bit, yeah. I mean, Anodyne
2 is 3D with 2D sections, and Anodyne 1 is
entirely 2D. Um, but the 3D sections in Anodyne
2 are definitely going for like a retro PS1-ish
era kind of feel.
Wayne: Yeah, that's the- I was watching some
of your streams, like I just peeked in and
out, and like, I saw some of those bits, like,
going between those two different aesthetics-
the PS1, or like N64 areas lookin' areas were
like really cool. Like, a lot of-- a lot of
articles 'n' shit and people are talking about
how like, that is- that's the era that we're
entering? Is like, oh yeah, we just went through
the 16 bit and like 32 bit, sort of, uhh...
there was that era of nostalgia and like kind
of bringing that aesthetic back, and now we're
in N64 and PS1 retro style games? And that's
fucking dope, I can't want to see more stuff
like that.
Trog: Yeah, to me, that's like, hey. That's...
Wayne: Prime.
Trog: I'm all, hit me with that nostalgia
bait for the N64 era because that's when I
was a kid, and that's what I have nostalgia
for. I've been playing a Banjo-Kazooie ROM
hack that turns all the areas of Ocarina of
Time into Banjo-Kazooie levels. That's...
Wayne: I saw!
Trog: That's how much... That's how much I
love the Nintendo 64. I'm playing mashup ROM
hacks now.
Gir: How is that?
Wayne: Is it all of Ocarina of Time?
Trog: It is a significant amount! It is basically
every area except for like, the fire temple.
It's like, pretty much the whole game.
Gir: [Crosstalk] Well, who cares about the
fire temple.
Wayne: Why'd they skip the fire temple?
Trog: I dunno. I remember reading something
that the devs said, and they were like, somebody
asked like, "Oh, are you ever gonna go back
and add in the fire temple- the fire temple
and the shadow temple, because neither of
those two are in?" And the dude was like,
"I literally can't. There's no more room in
the ROM."
[Baaulp laughs]
Wayne: I was thinking it might be something
like that.
Trog: "I used up every last byte available
for this ROM hack."
Gir: You'd have to- you'd probably have to
have Banjo-Kazooie get fucking dumped. Get
their ROMs, like...
Trog: Something, yeah. But hey, that-that
ROM hack's really good. I think it's called
Banjo-Kazooie: The Jiggies of Time, so...
if you, if you like 3D platformers, that one's
pretty dang good.
Log: I wonder if it's like, we're fixing to
run out of eras to be nostalgic for, really.
Baaulp: That's what I was gonna say!
Log: 'Cause yeah, like, 16 bit, alright, uh,
Nintendo 64, PlayStation 1 era, like once
you get to the PlayStation 2, GameCube whatever,
that's not really charming anymore.
Trog: Yeah.
Baaulp: Yeah, the graphics are like, the graphics
start to be, just like, "hey, we're trying
to be realistic", and now things are very
realistic looking games. But now it's like,
are we, like what... Maybe I can foresee,
I can foresee us being nostalgic for that,
but what is gonna happen with video games
graphics in the next 20 years that is gonna
make us re- uh, nostalgic for that?
Wayne: It won't happen.
Gir: The nostalgia factor will be for the
games themselves, rather than like, the style
of the game.
Baaulp: I guess, yeah.
Trog: Yeah.
Log: People are gonna get nostalgic for just
like the weird ass shovelware on the PS2.
Gir: I mean, obviously!
[Baaulp laughs]
Wayne: I mean, yeah. I think that like-
Trog: Yeah!
Wayne: -there could be that kind of, like,
era, for like PS2 games, but it'll be like
the shit- shit ones.
Trog: Yeah, whenever you're talking about
nostalgia for certain, like, you're right
in that it's not like the PS2, GameCube era,
it is specific PS2 GameCube games. 'Cause
whenever I think of stuff like that, I think
of games with a very specific, uh, visual
style. Like, you have Katamari, you have Jet
Set Radio...
Gir: Yeah.
Trog: You have like, you have these games
that went for a specific feel...
Wayne: And that's already happening!
Trog: Exactly! And you already see games,
that- that try to do that same kind of feel.
Wayne: Tho-those sort of nostalgia trip games
are already happening like, you have-you have
Lethal League and their new title that looks
like—that is literally just a spiritual
successor to Jet Set Radio, with Hideki Naganuma
doing the whole fuckin’ soundtrack.
Baaulp: Dude, someone needs to make—'cause
EA won’t—someone needs to make SSX, dude.
Make SSX!
Trog: Yeah.
Wayne: Our friend Brandon is doing Monkey
Ball. Like, they’re-they’re making a new
Monkey Ball!
Log: Yeah, if somebody made just like a game
that was like SSX3, I would be so down.
Baaulp: Yeah.
Wayne: That would be dope!
Gir: Wind Waker’s my case in point, by the
way. Look at how many things imitated Wind
Waker, in style and gameplay.
Baaulp: Yeah.
Log: Hold on a second, ‘cause we talked
about Jet Set Radio. It’s like, I love Hideki
Naganuma, they need to have more than just
him for that soundtrack, though.
Baaulp: Oh, yeah, like—
Log: People-people don’t-people don’t
know that like, Baaulp’s been playing the
original Jet Set Radio—
Baaulp: Uh-huh.
Log: Uh, people don’t realize just like,
how many people are on those soundtracks,
like—
Baaulp: Oh, yeah.
Log: —Jet Set Radio, the original, has Rob
Zombie Dragula in it.
Trog: Does it really?
Baaulp: Yeah, it has a remix of Rob Zombie’s
Dragula, it has a track from Jurassic 5 on
it, and it has like, a l—it has a—like,
Hideki Namanuma-Naganuma worked on the soundtrack,
but he is not the entirety of it, like, there
was a lot of love put into that. And honestly,
hey, I’m not-I’m not worried though, because
like, okay get Hideki Naganuma, awesome, uh,
just get like a whole bunch of, like, where-look
at the day and age we live in like, I don’t
listen to anyone on the top fi—I don’t
listen to anyone who’s been on a Billboard
chart, like-like yeah, just get like whoever
like, get—does their music sound good? Fit
the bill? Nice.
Wayne: Whether he-whether they-that he literally
does the whole soundtrack or if he’s just
like, or if he does a bunch of it and there
are other artists, I’m excited either way
because like they got him for like, the Lethal
League 2 soundtrack, but he only had one song.
Baaulp: Right.
Wayne: And it’s an amazing song, but I was
like, “Damn, I want more.” Some of these-some
of the songs in that game were fucking awesome.
Klaus Veen made like, a ton of tracks that
I now have like, hundreds of plays on Spotify
at this point. Like Ordinary Days, Candyman’s
theme? That’s the shit.
Log: Yeah, Bring-bring on-bring on Klaus Veen.
Wayne: I hope they do.
Log: Uh, get my boy Nanoray on there.
Wayne: That would be fuckin’ awesome! Oh,
man. I wish I knew those devs, I would be
like, “Yo, look at this guy.”
Baaulp: Yeah, just get-just get people-just
get—Yeah. Just like-like, just fuckin’
make this like, let people have their shot.
This is a cool chance. That game is so fuckin’
hard, it has not aged well.
Wayne: No, I couldn’t get into it the one
time I tried to play
it.
Baaulp: The gameplay it is—you can definitely
tell it was a game released in 2001. The controls
are like, so stiff, it’s so hard to do everything.
Log: You really are on rollerskates.
Baaulp: Yeah!
[Trog laughs]
Wayne: You gotta play Future, I hear that
one is better. The—
Baaulp: That one’s also stranded.
Wayne: Future’s inaccessible, like—
Baaulp: Yeah. The other thing that like, uh,
I wasn’t expecting, is that game to-to have
stayed relevant, because the first-the first
thing thatthe game says is like, “We’re-we’re
street punks, and the police are after us,”
and the police are like, pulling no punches.
They are literally shooting at you, they are
literally throwing grenades at you, teargas
[laughs]. It’s like, oh, I didn’t expect
this game to be this rele-dysto—
Wayne: That way.
Baaulp: Yeah, to hit that way.
Wayne: It does.
[Trog laughs]
Baaulp: I like, [laughs] I thought it was
just a “Grrr, these kids are-are messing
around with graffiti, we gotta-I dunno, throw
like a cartoon net over them, I-like—
[Trog and Wayne laugh]
Baaulp: I didn’t-I didn’t, like, when
they’re like, “We’re gonna start—”
Wayne: Uh-oh.
Baaulp: Yeah, like, they like, especially
in the first few levels they’re like, “Ah,
start teargassing ‘em,” I’m like, woah.
[Laughs] What? So, yeah, it’s a, weirdly
relevant, on that front.
Wayne: Uh, one more game before we move onto
other topics. I would say the one that we-a
lot of here have touchin’ and lookin’
at has been Risk of Rain 2, the 1.0 update.
Trog: Oh, yeah.
Wayne: The end has finally come, uh, and I
have a lot of thoughts, I mostly think it’s
dope, um, the final boss has some problems,
but I think overall I’m happy with it. Trog,
how do you feel about that final boss?
Trog: I think that Risk of Rain 2, the 1.0
update—Risk of Rain 2 as an entire gameplay
experience is great, I would recommend it
to anybody who likes third-person action games
and rogue-lites, I think it’s kind of obvious
if you’ve been keeping up with the game
and you’re coming into the 1.0 update from
the last one, I think you can kind of see
that they were definitely trying to hit a
deadline. I think that what they have added
in the 1.0 update is a little rough around
the edges, but it’s not bad in any way.
The game itself is not bad, it’s definitely
worth playing, I’m still—
Wayne: The game is great!
Trog: The game is great, I’m still enjoying
it.
Wayne: One of my favorite games of the past
few-like, past year or two. It came out in
early access, I don’t know if it’s my
game of the year, but.
Trog: But, the 1.0 update stuff is-feels uh,
uh slightly half-baked. It’s just not as
big of an update as you would expect from
like, a 1.0 release.
Wayne: You know why I can like, be like, biased
and like kind of brown-nose the update a little
bit? Ah, single-handedly is the-the fucking
composer made a sequel to Coalescence, which
is like, one of my favorite tracks in any
video game. The final-the final area of Risk
of Rain 1 has like, the most amazing track,
and the-the song they use for the final area
of Risk of Rain 2 is pretty much just like
a-like a—it is a reinterpretation of that
same
song, same motif, with a new spin and it’s
just as good. It’s-I would say maybe not
as good, but very, very close, and it’s
fucking awesome. That final area is so cool
visually with that music.
Log: Yeah, I think that the music was the
only thing that met the bar, really.
Trog: Yeah.
Log: I thought-I thought the rest didn’t
really meet standards. The-the final level
in Risk of Rain 1, like in Providence and
stuff, were just much better.
Wayne: It is-in terms of gameplay, yeah. Much
cooler. Risk of Rain 2, that area looks really
cool, but all it is is you run on a bridge
for five minutes and then you fight the boss.
Trog: Yeah.
Wayne: The like—I don’t know I, for whatever
reason, if you-if you play Risk of—Risk
of Rain 1, you can’t loop in the same way
you can loop in Risk of Rain 2, unless you
can, am I mixed up on that?
Log: Yeah, you can loop.
Wayne: You can loop? Okay, so Risk of Rain
1, let’s say you play the game for a while
and then you loop and then you play the game
for a while, and then you up deciding to go
to the final level. The-that last level is
fuckin’ crazy, like with how many enemies
there are and the difficulty like, and the
amount of items it gives you like-it’s like
one final power spike for
you while the game throws everything it has
at you. If you loop in Risk of Rain 2, you
will play like you’re-you’ll be on like
level nine or whatever, and there will be
overloading worms all other the place and
it’ll be crazy and you’ll be like, about
to die at all times, then you go to the final
level and there’s four enemies. I don’t-I
don’t know why, but like—
Trog: Yeah, it’s kinda lame.
Wayne: —The enem-the enemies there are cool
and strong, but it’s just like, does-I-it’s
so—
Trog: It’s very empty.
Wayne: It’s so barren. Yeah, it’s completely
empty.
Trog: And I feel like that’s by design.
Wayne: Yeah.
Trog: Like, maybe not from-maybe not by design
from a gameplay standpoint, but from like
a, y’know, either a narrative or just like
an aesthetic—
Wayne: It’s a-I think it’s a lore thing.
Trog: Yeah, either lore or aesthetic, they
wanted that area to feel empty, but that doesn’t
translate into super good gameplay, is the
thing.
Wayne: The final bosses’ name is literally
The King of Nothing, so I imagine that’s
why the Moon is like that.
Trog: Yeah. It’s probably an aesthetic thing,
which I-I can [unintelligible].
Wayne: [Crosstalk] And I think-I think with
how good-with
how good the gameplay is outside of like the-its-its-its
shortcomings there, I think-I think it’s-I
think it’s okay that they leaned for the
aesthetic more than like, the actual final
level being—
Trog: Sure. Because the thing is that you
don’t really get
anything for beating the final boss… more
than once. You unlock a new character
when you beat it once and I think you should
get something for beating it on Monsoon.
Wayne: [Crosstalk] On each difficulty! You
get one of-you get one of the craziest blue
items if you beat it on Monsoon, I have yet
to do it. I’m excited to do it.
Trog: So, so it’s like you can honestly
kind of ignore that and play the game like
how you played it before the update, where
you’re just going for the longest run possible
which I think is more fun, I think it’s
more
fun to just see how far and how crazy of a
build you can get rather than just
going for the final boss or whatever.
Wayne: Yeah. But there are—Yeah, and-but-and
I-and I like that you can use the two together,
like you can go like super long and then when
it’s
like, “Okay, I’m starting to get bored,
let’s go see how-if I can take on the
final boss like this,” ‘cause the final
boss keeps getting stronger, too. Like
the longer that you keep playing.
Trog: [Crosstalk] Yeah.
Wayne: And that-when it comes to that fight—we
haven’t actually talked about the boss itself
that much—uh, that boss has some bullshit
in there, especially the first time that you
fight it—Hey, if you’re listening now,
and you haven’t played it yet, wh-when the
boss jumps you need to jump. You need to stay
in the air for like, at least like, ten seconds.
When he lands, you will die if you’re on
the ground.
Trog: Yeah.
Wayne: We’re telling you that now because
some of our friends were not told that and
they were very mad. In fact, Trog here had
that experience, um—
Trog: It’s just the kind of thing where
the final boss design seems a little incongruous
with the rest of the boss design and the enemy
design in the game, in that it feels like
they were making a Dark Souls boss for a game
where it takes you thirty minutes to get to
the final boss, right?
Wayne: Mhmm.
Trog: Like, it’s not like Dark Souls where
it’s like, alright, you can have your boss
have bullshit one-hit attacks in Dark Souls,
because you die and you’re at the bonfire
and you spend thirty seconds walking back
to the
boss fight and you just try it again. But
that doesn’t work in a rogue-like where
it’s like, alright, I’ve got a good build
for the first-like, I’ve done
ten runs, this if the first run in ten runs
where I have a good build, I’m
gonna go, I’m gonna do the boss—It just
did something that I have no idea it
could have done, and I’m dead. And now my
run is over.
Wayne: Other-other rogue-lites like, when
you—the-the-the-the
thing is is like, some-some other games it
takes just as long to get to the final boss,
like the-the Dead Cell’s final boss you
have to play the game for a long time to get
there, and that boss is hard as fuck, I’ve
never beaten it.
Trog: [Crosstalk] That is true.
Wayne: Um, the uh, like I think-I think the
amount of time that you have to go there,
in my opinion, is-can be both infuriating,
but I think the fact that so much like-so
much of your time and effort weighs on
like, how you manage to fair I think is like,
it’s fitting to me, and it-it
makes it cool. Like, the-the time where I
actually did it, like the-the one time I beat
the final boss—like, I cheesed it a little
bit at the beginning, but when you get to
the very final stage—spoilers, if you don’t
want me spoiling the boss—the very final
stage of the boss is he takes away all of
your items and you have to fight him raw while
you progress and try to get your items back.
And I was like, I had like a kind of weak
build, I was jumping around, I was hitting
him with lightning whenever I could, and when
I got to that phase I was like, “Fuck, it’s
on.” And I jumped up and got in front of
his face and just fuckin’ like, APM’d
the shit out of him with Mercenary and I managed
to kill him, like, while he was giving me
my items back, like, before he took everything
or whatever, and it felt so good to finally
get it done.
Trog: I think that final phase is honestly
one of the things I really don’t like about
it, because every time I’ve gotten-every
time I’ve attempted the final boss and gotten
to that final phase and I didn’t have some
sort of cheese strategy, or I wasn’t playing
a character that has a mobility skill, you
just get hosed, man. Like, I tried doing it—
Wayne: Certain characters can’t do it.
Trog: Yeah, I tried doing it as REX and it’s
like, I am too sl—like, he takes every single
one of your items, right?
Wayne: Yeah.
Trog: REX is a character that has no-or limited
mobility. Like, and slow to begin with.
Wanye: [Crosstalk] I almost did it as REX.
Trog: So it’s like, I can’t dodge the
attacks and then I just die. And it’s like,
the devs even said like, people were talking
about how the third phase was bullshit, and
the devs even came out in like a blogpost
and said like, “Yeah, the third phase wasn’t
supposed to be the hard part of that fight,
the third phase was just supposed to be kind
of like uh, ‘oh shit’ moment the first
time it happens, but it wasn’t supposed
to be like what you…
like gear up for,” so I think they will
probably end up tweaking that.
Log: Yeah, a lot of it just didn’t seem
very thought out.
Like the-the-the death island that you could
go to and softlock your game.
Trog: Yeah, there was a-there was an island
where you just
softlock.
Wayne: There’s just an island where if you
go on it, at
least in like the-before they patched it,
I still don’t know if they have. If
you didn’t have enough mobility skills,
you would just get stuck, and it happened
to me and Erarg when we were playing once,
and like, I-we literally like—I had
mobility, he didn’t, so he was just stuck
over there and I watched him struggle
and I was like, “Okay, we’re gonna find
out how the fuck to get you out of this,”
because if you’re in multiplayer, you can’t
spawn the final boss until everyone’s
there, and he had no way to suicide because
when you jump off the ledge it only
brings you down to one health. So what we
did was I had him like, jump, and
then I walked under him—No, I had-I had
him jump on top of me because you have
like a physical hitbox for other players,
and then I had him jump and then I
double-jumped, and hitting him restored his
jumps, so like, I boosted him off
my head to the final boss and it took us like
ten minutes to get it right. It
was-it was bullshit.
Log: Had to enact troll physics to play the
game [laughs].
Trog: Yeah. There’s just-I think—yeah.
Like I said at the
beginning of the conversation, I think it’s
obvious they were trying to hit a
deadline, they were set on that deadline—and
I respect them for sticking to the
deadline, but I feel like this is a situation
where maybe they could’ve said like,
“Hey guys, I know we had we had this date,”
and who knows, maybe it was out of their
control, I don’t know who their publisher
is it could be that they had to release
it—
Log: Gearbox.
Trog: Yeah, so maybe it was like, maybe the
date was totally
out of their hands, but I feel like this would
have been a situation where it
would have been okay to be like, “Hey guys,
we need like, another month. Like,
trust us, it’ll be good, but we just need
one more month and then we’ll release
it.” And I feel like that-that’ll be good.
Again, not that I dislike the game
in any way, I think that it’s great, I would
highly recommend it, but just-if
you’ve been keeping up with the game, the
1.0 update is a little half-baked.
Wayne: Now that Risk of R-chat-Rain is over,
Gir, what have
you been playing?
Gir: Fuck all.
Trog: Alright.
Wayne: Really, video games aren’t doing
it for you these days?
Gir: If it’s not been on stream, I’ve
not really played anything.
I’ve done hardly anything off stream lately.
Wayne: Hmm.
Gir: I think the only thing in the last few
days I’ve played
is literally because it came out like last
night, was Flight Simulator.
Wayne: Yeah, have you-how much of that did
you touch?
Gir: Uh… enough to know that I really should
just have a
flight stick.
Wayne: Is it-is it cool, though? Like, the—
Gir: Yeah, I mean it’s cool.
Wayne: Does it not play well with the Xbox
controller?
Gir: Eh, it doesn’t play well with my Xbox
controller.
Wayne: Oh. What’s wrong with yours?
Gir: My stick is like, o—it’s like, really
fucked up oversensitive stick.
Wayne: Mhmm.
Gir: Uh, it’s got uh, drift on it and everything.
And you don’t want drift when you’re trying
to keep a fucking plane straight.
Wayne: Yeah.
Gir: So, yeah, I think if I get into that
game more I’ll have to like, invest in a
flight stick of some kind.
Wayne: I uh, saw some funny shit from that
game already. And
like, the concept is super interesting with
like, them having the whole world
mapped out with satellite data, you can go
anywhere, like that’s pretty-it’s-you
see that—
Trog: I can go to my house?
Wayne: You see that country? You can fly to
it.
Gir: I did take the time to fly over my house.
Wayne: You can! You can go to your house!
Gir: Yeah.
Wayne: Someone found Grover House, like that’s-you
can—
[Gir laughs]
Baaulp, laughing: Holy shit! Holy shit!
Wayne: Yeah, you can go to Grover House, you
can-there—I saw
on Tumblr a post that was like, the game is
multiplayer, and it-it’s like—Gir,
is it like server based or is it just like
you see other people playing
the game, it’s like just a wide—like Sea
of Thieves.
Gir: It’s like a shard-based type deal.
Wayne: Yeah! So it’s like-it’s like Sea
of Thieves.
Gir: Yeah.
Wayne: Like-that’s-that’s fuckin’ dope.
The post that I saw
was like-like a bunch of planes landed on
an island and the caption was like, “Yeah,
everyone is just flying to Epstein’s island.
We’re gonna solve this ourselves.”
[Baaulp laughs]
Wayne: There were like eight biplanes landed
on Epstein’s island.
Yeah, I might have to check it out even though
I’m not usually into those kind
of games, especially because it’ll get VR
support soon.
Baaulp: It seems like, with that in that context
like, “Oh
yeah, we have the entire world mapped out,”
it seems like really dope to just
explore.
Gir: Yeah.
Baaulp: I would love to just-to just like-yeah,
find my own
house and just like, go around and uh—
Gir: The thing to remember though is it is—everything
is to scale. So, if you want to get somewhere
that would take two hours to fly to, it is
going to take two hours to fly there.
Trog: That’s pretty wild.
Baaulp: But-but like-but like, who cares.
Yeah, who cares.
Like, fuck it.
Gir: Hell, I mean if that’s what you want
to do, then you do
that, by all means.
Wayne: Can I play like, super mode. Can I
play hyper mode
where I fly like, a jet rocket and I [laughs].
Gir: I mean, there is a jet.
Baaulp: You can like-you can get out of your
plane too, is
that correct?
Gir: No.
Trog: You can’t jump out of your plane while
it’s moving?
Log: It’s like-it’s like Tony Hawk’s
Underground.
Wayne: That’s a-that’s a shame, there’s
no like-there’s no like
Test Drive Unlimited 2 element, like that
would be pretty cool.
Baaulp: If that was available y’know what
I’d do, I’d just
like-I’d just like fly over my own house
and jump out and like, land on my own
house [laughs].
[Wayne laughs]
Log: They added in a feature where if you
crash your plane
your pilot can get out, and if you mash a
button fast enough it raises his rage
meter and he can do a sick trick to destroy
his plane.
Wayne: [Laughs] He breaks the plane in half.
He steps on the
plane and smashes it to pieces.
Gir: I will say they-they have some like,
they have a lot of
like variety in the like how-how easy do you
want this to be. Do you want this
to be an arcade game or do you want this to
be a straight fucking simulator. So
you can turn off all of the like—you can
fly straight into the ground if you
want, you can fuckin’ do backflips all day
long—
Wayne: Can you like, is there cool destruction
if you have like-like
all the rules on, if you fly into the ground
do you get like fuckin’
obliterated?
Gir: If you fly too sharply, the game just
says, “Hey, you
flew so hard that you would have ripped the
wings off of a real plane. Therefore,
it is over. Restart.
[Trog laughs]
Wayne: Aw, you don’t get any animation?
That-that’s—aw, come
on.
Gir: You don’t get any animation—It just
cuts to black, you
hear like a-like a VRRRrrrrr, like a—
Wayne: You have to watch like a PSA about
why you shouldn’t
fly like that.
[Gir and Log laugh]
Wayne: You fucked up. All your passengers
are dead. Yeah, I’ll
have to-I’ll have to look into that. But
yeah, uh, another thing I wanted to
talk about, like, based on something you said,
you said like, “Yeah, you haven’t
been playing a whole lot of games off stream
lately,” uh, since May, which was
when our last podcast was, uh, our Twitch
Team, Radio TV Solutions, has really kicked
into gear. I think around that time was probably
when we actually formed it,
right? Like it would have been around May.
Around-around the time—
Baaulp: Yeah, yeah.
Trog: Uhh…
Gir: June.
Trog: June, yeah.
Wayne: May-man-June, so yeah. Like, all of
us stream now,
uh, some of us more than others. Uh, and it
has been a lot of fun, it’s been-I
feel like we’ve all been having a good chunk
of success, it’s been a good time.
Uh, the—one thing I want to talk about here
a little bit, is like, Gir I feel
like you in particular, like you’ve been
doing like, a ton of streaming. Like,
and you said that—
Gir: Oh, yeah.
Wayne: You-you-you said that-you said that
you haven’t been
playing a whole lot off stream because you’ve
been doing so much on stream. The—how
do you like, at-at-at—Do you ever see that
becoming a problem? Like-like, in
the way of like, some streamers that I know
who stream all the fuckin’ time
talk about how like video games are like shot
for them because of streaming. Like,
if they’re not-if they’re playing a game
off stream they can’t help but hear
that nagging voice in their head like, “I
should be streaming this.” And it
makes them-it makes the games hard to enjoy.
Gir: Yeah, uh—
Wayne: Are you-are any of you-I’ll talk
to all of you guys
here—
Gir: I’ve already started feeling that,
to an extent. Like, I
will-I will get a game and it’s like, “Oh,
this is gonna be a fun game, I
should probably stream this, though—”
Wayne: And then like if you-and then like-for-for
me, this
might be the same for you, Gir, is like, I
get that thought, and it doesn’t necessarily
make the game not fun for me, but it makes
it more stressful, I’m like, “Damn,
I could be, there could be so many ‘haha
funny’ moments if I were playing this
on stream. This could be such a good entertaining
game for the folks,” and I
just have that stress of like, and I misusing
my time, here? So far, hasn’t
ruined it for me. Baaulp, what were you saying?
Baaulp: I-I am privy to that. I try to avoid
it, and the way I avoid it is that I kind
of like, I kind of in my mind, at the-at the
risk of sounding egotistic, in my mind I like,
I tell myself that I’m the show. Not the
games, I am. So whatever game I play is whatever
people will want to watch, and that’s-that—I’ve
been able-for example, there’s been no-I’ve
like, there are some games that I keep to
myself, not be-not because I’m like, “Ooh,
this is my game and the audience doesn’t
get to see this,” but like, “Oh, no one’s
gonna wanna watch me play Magic the Gathering.”
Like, that’s not, y’know what I mean?
Wayne: I feel like I can do both reasons.
Like I have some games
where I-I don’t stream it because like,
I don’t think this would make for an
entertaining stream, like Risk of Rain 2,
for instance. I streamed it when it
launched because that was like an event, but
other than that, that game doesn’t—like
nobody really—like it’s kind of just us
y’know, going at it, doing the grind.
Baaulp: Yeah.
Wayne: There’s not anything like to talk
about, there’s nothing
special there.
Baaulp: Yeah like ga—like yeah. And then
like, uh, for
example, I’ll stream Tekken all the time,
and I’ll play it myself and like, the
enjoyment with that has not changed at all.
Gir: For me it’s more a matter of if I’m
playing something
off stream, and something really fucking funny
happens, I just feel that hint
of regret that I had no clue of it ever happening.
Wayne: Yeah, I’ve had that happen, too.
Sometimes-sometimes that also—that’ll
happen in a game-like I’ve had some crazy
shit happen in Fall Guys where it’s like,
“I fucking wish I was recording that,”
like that doesn’t make any sense. Then also,
that’ll happen even when we’re not playing
games. Like there’ll just be a really funny
conversation and like, I’m like, “Damn,
that would have been good if we were recording
this somehow. Like that would have been a
good moment to preserve.”
Baaulp: I-I don’t think it’s healthy to
have that want—Like for me, in my mind,
I guess that’s because I like come from
like, I guess I’m more professional like—every
job I’ve had before this has been like very
professional. And like, clear separation of
like, “Hey, maybe there’s some overlap
here, but this is my time versus work time.”
Wayne: Oh, yeah. And I mean, I have that too,
but because-the nature-the nature of this
job, the nature of what we do just means that
there is like, like you can try to make sure
that there’s little overlap, but like there-there
just is overlap. One of my biggest hobbies
is video games, that is also my job. That
overlap is just inherent. I was gonna—
Trog: [Crosstalk] I um, I don’t stream—Oh,
sorry.
Wayne: I was going to ask you the question
next. I feel like your approach, Trog, in
streaming on this team has been different
from
everybody else’s. When playing games, at
least.
Trog: Yeah, I don’t know. I don’t plan
on streaming as like a
source of income, I—
Wayne: You’re the producer.
Trog: The way that I have been tackling Twitch
is like, do I
think this will be entertaining for people?
If so, I’ll stream it. Or if, y’know
sometimes, I feel like the thing with um,
the turning point for a Twitch stream
is when you have enough people in your chat
that you can keep up a conversation
with them. ‘Cause we-we do a lot of Twitch
viewing of literal zero viewer Twitch
streams and it’s like, if you are streaming
to an audience of zero, you are
simply playing a video game, right?
Wayne: Mhmm.
Trog: You’re not really doing anything,
I feel like the
turning point is whenever you can get enough
viewers that there’s somebody, y’know
like a handful of people that will talk in
the chat and you can have some sort
of dialogue with them. And I feel like we
are all at that level now, but for me
I’m not doing it as a source of income,
so I’m basically just selling my emotes
to people, is how I kind of tackle it.
Wayne: [Laughs] That’s fun.
Trog: It’s like, look, I am an affiliate,
therefore I have
emotes, I want emotes so that I can use them,
so if you want, you can buy these
emotes from me for five dollars.
Wayne: When you play your games, there’s
like, you-like, I
notice when like, watching your streams, you
are very much more showcasing
like, sharing the game that you’re playing
and sharing the experience and like-like-like
alongside the chat and like, you will go long
stretches of silence like just
focusing on the game, right? Like—
Trog: Sure. So, for instance I streamed Anodyne
2 and I
like, basically just didn’t talk for any
of that just because like what-what do
you say? Like, I-the thing that I’m self-conscious
about with streaming is that
I-I don’t want to fall into that like generic
streamer mode where it’s just like,
y’know, y’know what the jokes are where
it’s like, “Oh, look at the character!
Look
at it go! Oh, it’s crazy, they performed
a jump! Oh man, this is cra-oh,
you-you-can you guys see this? Oh, this is
crazy.” And there’s just like,
fucking nothing going on stream and it’s
like, “This dude is a psychopath, he’s
just-he’s just saying anything!”
[Baaulp laughs]
Gir: You gotta learn to be comfortable with
silence every now
and then.
Wayne: My streams like, my streams have like-like
I try-I
try to-I try to evoke a higher energy, like,
I like chaos. I like intense moments
and shit like that, but like, the-when it
comes-when nothing’s happening like,
I’ll still try to talk but like, I’m not
gonna-I’m not—that’s like-I feel like
what you just described is like, Markiplier
syndrome.
Gir, laughing: It’s a syndrome.
Trog: I-what I just did does not describe
anybody on our Twitch
Team, just for the record.
Wayne: Yeah.
Gir: Markiplier disorder.
Trog: That’s like-that is describing a human
that none of us
are. Like—
Wayne: Yeah [laughs].
Trog: That is like, a specific breed of like—and
I just feel
like, for me it’s like, yeah, y’know,
I want to let the game talk for itself. And
I’ll-I’ll like say out loud what my thought
process is if I’m like, y’know, for
instance, okay, I’m playing the Banjo-Kazooie
ROM hack or whatever, I’m like
thinking out loud like, “Alright I need
to get-I’m gonna go grab these notes, I
saw some stuff over there,” but I’m not
like commenting on every single thing
that the character is doing, and I don’t
know. That just-that works for me.
Wayne: [Crosstalk] Mhmm. Everybody got their
own approach.
Trog: I think people-I want people to enjoy
the more laidback
attitude and I think I-I think I can bring
that to the group, at least.
Wayne: Oh, yeah. For sure. I—If I get one
piece of criticism
that like, I-my stream’s—it’s definitely
valid, and like, a lot of like, the
different members of the team, you could avoid
that by watching their stream
instead of mine, people are like, “Yeah,
when I watch Wayne’s streams I get
overstimulated and it like, hurts my head.”
[Baaulp laughs]
Trog: Yeah.
Wayne: ‘Cause like a lot of the times, depending
on what the stream is and what we’re doing,
it can be that way. The—and it’s like,
sometimes it’s a good thing, sometimes it’s
the best thing, and I love it. And other times
it’s wholly like, unintentional, like I’m
just trying to like manage the amount of alerts
like, with the music, with the game, with
the-with our dialogue.
Log: You mean people don’t wanna see a combination
Destiny 2 Runescape stream?
[Trog and Wayne laugh]
Wayne: I need to do another one of those.
The—I, yeah. Like
those-those are the times yes, those are the
times where I’m trying to overstimulate
you, I’m trying to make your head explode
through Twitch. The uh, but yeah-but I’m-I’m-I’m
getting better at like, finding a sort of
like, a median where like, okay, alerts are
not going to like literally make it impossible
for you to focus on like the dialogue, like
certain streams I just have to forego like,
maybe get a little bit less income but like,
the show can be better.
Gir: Yeah, I will say I personally-I tried—
Wayne: You just turned off TTS.
Gir: I tried the text-to-speech thing for
like, I dunno, like three or four weeks, and
I was like, I can already see this snowballing
to the point where I just can’t pay attention
anymore. Like forget anyone else watching,
I wasn’t able to pay attention, so.
Wayne: In my chat, when it works right, like,
it is a great way for me to have discussions
better. Like just because the size of the
chat is so big that I can have those dialogues
that like, you were talking about, but the
problem is that it’s splintered. If I’m
having a conversation with chat it is usually
not the same person, but rather the chat talking
to me collectively.
Trog: Yeah. Exactly. But that’s what happens
when you have like,
a viewership that is an order of magnitude
bigger than like—
Wayne: Yeah, yeah. It’s just inherent.
Trog: You have your zero view streams, you
have your like,
tier one—like you two years ago, like twenty
to fifty people.
Wayne: Yeah.
Trog: Then you have like tier two, fifty to
like, I would
say even up to like three or four hundred
people. A chat is pretty much the
same from like, fifty to four hundred people,
in my opinion.
Wayne: Mhmm.
Trog: But then like, you reach like, that
four-digit number
and it’s just like, the chat is unreadable
at that point.
Wayne: Then you enter Twitch jungle. That’s-that’s
video
jungle.
Gir: Chat’s only good for turning into a
pogchamp.
Trog: It just turns into like, an-an atomic
bomb.
Wayne: [Laughs] I like both kinds of chats.
And I’ve noticed
too, like, I can have a chat start like that,
and then if I let the stream go
on too long into weird hours, I can like,
go back down to a tier two style
chat, like when I did-when I did the Dark
Souls-I did the Dark Souls San Andreas
stream when I streamed for ten hours ‘till
like 9AM and uh, that was really fun
because the chat did slow down and I got to
have like, more conversations.
Gir: Yeah, your chat was nice and-nice and
calm that whole
time.
Wayne: Nice and calm.
Trog: Yeah.
Wayne: It’s fun-it’s fun to do a chill
stream occasionally,
but the-I do-I do thrive on the chaos. Uh,
and then—so, and then I guess the
only person I haven’t directly asked about
the streams here is Log. Log, you
have, like, your main streams like, you’ve
been streaming Hylics 2, right? But
then you, you’ve-you’ve been doing the
art streams lately—Did you do a Gather
Ye Power stream this week?
Log: Yeah. Um, that’s what I did on Sunday
before I started
playing Hylics.
Wayne: So, Log is a totally different niche
covered in art, none of us are doing that.
Log: Yeah, it’s kind of a weird thing ‘cause
it’s like, I don’t
think it’s something that people are generally
interested in, and like, I-I get
it, ‘cause like even I’m not interested
in that necessarily, like, um, the-the
guy who makes One-Punch Man, um—
Gir: ONE?
Log: Uh no, Yusuke Murata.
Gir: Oh.
Log: He-he does stream him working on the
new chapters, but
like, even if I was interested, I don’t
really want to like, tune in.
Gir: [Crosstalk] Huh!
Log: I don’t really, feel the-the need to
watch the process
in real-time, ‘cause when you get down to
it, art is just-it’s slow. Like, you’re
just there to have a little chat, really.
Wayne: Mhmm.
Trog: Yeah.
Log: Uhm, and whenever I’m working on it
I just tend to
mumble to myself what I’m doing, so that’s
not really like, the best viewer
experience. However, um, after switching over
to Hylics 2 and playing a little
bit of that on stream for the first time,
I feel like that’s like, what feels
most natural to me. ‘Cause like, I think
the way that I work is that whenever I
am-am knowledgeable about something in a game
I will like-I will just kind of
like, gush about it, and then whenever it
gets into the stuff that I’m not as
knowledgeable about it, it’s much easier
for something like Hylics where I just
get to just like, see it and handle it at
whatever pace. It gives me time to like
just think about what’s going on.
Gir: Oh, yeah, I feel that.
Trog: Personally, I really like the art streams
because they’re
just kind of like, well, it’s different
for me than the viewers because
whenever you’re doing an art stream I can
just pop in and like have a chat,
like, for real—
Wayne: Mhmm.
Trog: But I feel that it’s like-it’s kind
of that atmosphere
where it’s like, you’re right, art is
slow, but that means that if you aren’t
paying full attention, you aren’t going
to miss anything. Like, it really is
just something to turn on and listen to and
be like, “I’m gonna listen to these
people have a conversation,” y’know. It’s
kind of like a podcast in itself.
Wayne: And also, Log’s got that baller taste
in music. So
that also helps.
Trog: Yeah, the music’s good. It’s fun
to play stream DJ. I’ve
been having a lot of fun just finding cool
music I like to play at the start of
my stream, that’s always fun.
Wayne: Mhmm.
Log: Like, that-that—I feel like part of
the thing where I
like these kind of RPG games, especially the
ones like Hylics that are just
very interesting to see visually, is that
I don’t really like, think in terms
of what’s really going on, I don’t know,
it just feels very—
Trog: Abstract?
Log: It just feels very nat-it just feels
very natural to just
like, determine something completely-just
come up with something just completely
different than what’s just on screen.
Trog: Mhmm.
Log: I don’t-I don’t know-I don’t know
how to like, I don’t
know how to-how to properly describe it. It
just feels funnier.
Trog: Heh.
Log: Just because it’s-it just feels inherently
funny just
because of like, being able to slow it down
and take in all the stuff and see
all the weird things.
Trog: Yeah.
Wayne: Mhmm.
Trog: I mean that’s-that’s definitely—I
mean, that’s how Scorpy streams every game.
Scorpy-Scorpy basically patented the, “stop
everything that I am doing in the game and
zoom in on something weird on the screen,”
like—
Wayne: [Laughs] He was doing that-he was doing
that long before we were even like, thinking
of like having a Twitch Team and doing this
as a group. Like, Scorpy—I like-I have such
a vivid memory of a Scorpy stream from like,
three years ago where we were watching him
play a game called like, Sphinx the Curse
of the Mummy or something like that. It’s
just this horrible-it’s not even horrible,
it’s just mediocre PS2 platformer where
you play as like, some kid in Egypt and you
jump around and like, I’ll never forget
like, just this-this time where he just stopped
the stream, was just like, silent for three
minutes, and then zooms in on a sarcophagus
and just pops up a little notepad window and
it says—and it just said, I probably have
the screenshot somewhere, it just said in
plain text, all caps, “ENTERING THE SARCOPHAGUS
WILL
KILL HIM” and it just hung on that for like
two minutes.
Trog: [Laughs] Yeah.
Wayne: I will never forget that.
Gir: Something I want to say is uh, had things
been different,
in terms of the ability to travel, I guarantee
you I would have been doing
fishing streams every now and then.
Trog: Yeah.
Wayne: That’d be fun.
Baaulp: Ohhh, damn.
Gir: Had I had the opportunity to go on my
vacation that I originally
was gonna go on, I definitely would have done
that like, several times.
Wayne: So, I have like a number of IRL stream-type
stuff
like that that I’ve wanted to do, and like
people are always saying, “Wayne, woods
stream?” Like that’s the meme, that’s
the joke. Like they always ask me for
woods stream. And I always say “I’ll give
you woods stream one day,” which will
be a stream where I will walk around the woods.
There have like those streaming
backpacks you can buy that are like twenty-five
hundred dollars and like, honestly
like, that might be a good investment one
day if I want to do more of this, but
that’s a good segue. Just recently—
Gir: Segway, you say.
Wayne: [Laughs] I didn’t, I don’t have
a Segway. The-just recently,
I’ve-I keep talking about it on stream like,
“Oh yeah, I’m getting into a
hobby,” and like I-like I haven’t wanted
to tell people about it because I wasn’t
sure one hundred percent if I could pull it
off, I wasn’t-I maybe wanted it to
be a surprise like if I did a stream with
it, and I think one day I’ll maybe do
streams with it, the—I uh, just last week,
uh, got-I received my first ever
electric unicycle, uh-the, which is a personal
electric vehicle.
Wayne: Think a hoverboard-kind of like a hoverboard,
but one
wheel, much more powerful, much more serious.
Uh, the-it, I got it last week on
Friday, and I have been absolutely obsessed
with it since like… when would it have
been… I think-I think I-I figured it out
um, Satur-it was Sunday—No, no, no,
Sunday is when I figured it out, Sunday’s
when it clicked, and Sunday is when
it like-I just fell in fuckin’ love with
it. I got it Friday night and I was in
the call here I-I took it outside and uh,
I put it up, put it up behind my car.
Like, the first steps you’re supposed to
take with the electric unicycle is like,
you’re supposed to support yourself against
a wall, stand on it, and just like
wheel back and forth and just like feel what
that’s like. And I was doing that,
and then like, I had never felt more exhausted
just like jumping on that thing,
standing on it for two seconds, and then falling
off. It was like, killing me.
I was-I like-I-I like couldn’t catch my
breath for like three minutes, it was
bad.
Wayne: Um, and then I, just this last weekend
I went away
for a funeral, and uh, we were at-we were
at the funeral home and like we did
our stuff for a few good hours, paid our respects,
and I went outside to like
practice, and I got like so discouraged because
I was like, trying to do it and
it was just like, hurting the shit out of
me, and I couldn’t pull off like anything.
The—Whe-whe-when you guys were young, how
long did it take you to learn how to
ride a bike? Do you think? Or do-do—
Gir: God, I don’t remember, you kidding
me?
Baaulp: I don’t remember.
Trog: Yeah, I don’t know.
Baaulp: At this point I haven’t rode a bike
in so long I
think-I think I’ve gone back down to zero.
Wayne: You fuckin’ like—this is off-topic,
this is a tangent,
too, but you-you obviously know the saying,
you know the saying, like, “You never
forget how to ride a bike.” If I gave you
a bike, do you think you could ride
it right now? Well?
Baaulp: No. No [laughs].
Wayne: I feel like I couldn’t, either. I
feel like-like—
Trog: Really? I absolutely could ride a bike
still.
Log: No idea.
Wayne: Maybe-I mean I’ve been building up
my balance with
this thing so maybe I could do it, but like,
so, the first night I put in an hour, I could
maybe stay on the wheel for like, three seconds
before I’d have to jump
off of it. Second day, I couldn’t even get
that. I don’t-I don’t know why. I’ve
been using this forum, which is a bizarre
experience because it is literally like a
PHB internet forum, it’s crazy that it still
exists and it’s not like some other kind
of-like a-like a Reddit community or whatever.
Trog: Other than Discord.
Wayne: Yeah-yeah it’s not just a Discord,
it’s like an
actual genuine forum, it feels fuckin’ weird.
It’s like I’m going back in time.
But like, I was-I was asking for tips and
doing research, and like, the-the
advice that I got, there were-there were three
prevailing pieces of advice. The-in
order to learn how to ride an electric unicycle.
The-the first piece of advice
was uh, don’t try to do it alone. Like,
much like a child riding a bike, much
how your dad or your mom would like hold you
and then let you go, you need to
do that. You need to have someone to hold
your hand and then like, you need to
like put weight on them as you-as you ride
like a good like, twenty-or-so feet.
The second piece of advice was in order to
brake, you need to just like, you
need to sit down. Like you just need to pretend
to sit down. Or else you will like—it
will just not fuckin’ work. ‘Cause the
first problem I was having was anytime I
tried to stop, I would just start accelerating
and turning and it was so scary.
[Trog laughs]
Wayne: The, uh, like-like the way an electric
unicycle works
is you learn forward to go fast and accelerate,
like you put pressure on like,
the ball of your foot, and to stop you put
it on your heels. But you have to,
you have to know how to distribute your body
weight properly in order to do
that. So I don’t know what I was doing,
I think I was trying to like,
push back on my heels and like—but then
I was putting more pressure on the ball
of my feet too, because I didn’t want to
fall off, like-I-like I think I was
trying to like, lift my toes, which would
have like killed me, so it was just making
me go super fast and spinning in circles,
and I almost ate shit a few times.
[Trog laughs]
Trog: Do you feel like you’re a more clownlike
individual
after purchasing this unicycle?
Baaulp: [Crosstalk] Yeahhhh, that’s the
real question.
Wayne: That’s the thing. I keep walking
into it. I keep like-like,
I was just like joking around with my friends,
I just said like, like in an
excited voice one day, I was just like, “I’m
going to go ride my unicycle,”
[Baaulp and Log laugh]
Wayne: And there was like-someone was like,
“Okay, Bozo,” like-fuckin’, [laughs]
it was just—so now I’m kind of—
Trog: Wayne is becoming a clownlike individual,
this is
all-look, it’s fine, you wanted to be a
cl-you’ve told us you’ve always wanted
to be a clown, I’ve always been supportive—
[Baaulp and Wayne laugh]
Gir: I know-we know you dropped out of clown
college.
Trog: Buying this unicycle is the first step,
I’m going to
get you a set of balloon animal balloons for
your birthday—
[Wayne laughs]
Baaulp: Did someone like accidentally drop
a bunch of fruit
like, on you and the-from like a higher elevation
and then you just like instant-and
then you just instantly started juggling like
a bunch of apples [laughs].
Wayne: [Laughs] Juggling it? I was-okay, I-I
didn’t
catch on that that was where you were going
with that and was like, what the
fuck are you talking about? I thought-I—No,
I thought like, my-my-the first
thing I was thinking was like, “Is he going
to make some sort of joke
about like, getting hit with fruit makes you
a clown?” Like—
[Gir laughs]
Trog: Well, getting hit with fruit does make
you a
clown, let’s be honest.
[Baaulp and Wayne laugh]
Trog: All I’m saying is that, unicycle step
one, balloon
animal step two, pulling infinite scarves
out of your mouth step three.
Wayne: Hey, your hands are totally free on
any unicycle, so
I could learn to juggle on it.
Baaulp: Well it’s a-it’s an electric unicycle
so we keep
joking that you’ll be some type of cyber-clown.
Wayne: That’d be dope. So, but I’ve been-I’ve
been givin’ in
to the clown jokes because it is funny, like,
I’ll just say like, I’ve-I’ve
just said like-I-I-I was in the Discord the
other day and I think I said
something along the lines I was like, “Guys,
I think I’m addicted to this unicycle
and getting into small cars.” And like [laughs]—
[Baaulp laughs]
Trog: It’s true. Wayne is becoming a clownlike
individual.
Wayne: Alright, but the opposite effect is
happening—
Log: I’m imagining like, a clown rolling
in with a-with a-like
a squirt flower that fires that one like,
high powered laser [laughs] instead
of water.
[Trog laughs]
Wayne: [Laughs] Like the fucking-like the
fucking-like WEEDO
advertised one?
Log, laughing: Yeah.
[Wayne laughs]
Log: Just burns things into wood.
Wayne: Burns things very slowly, [laughs]
like it’s just-like
I-like I-I squeeze my little flower and very
slowly light you on fire, you have
to stand still.
Gir: [Crosstalk] James Bond type clown.
Wayne: [Laughs] Yeah. Um, but yeah, so the
second piece of
advice was yes, sit down to brake, which worked
amazingly, and the third piece of
advice was don’t just-don’t do it on like
a street, do it in like a parking
lot, in an open area because like, much like
a bike-like, if you-if you try-if
you try to just go straight and that’s your
first objective, you’re gonna fail.
When you-when you feel like you’re going
to fall just like on a bike, you have
to like turn into it. So I ended up like swervin’
around a little bit. And on
Sunday I was like, we-we were-it was a family
trip so I asked my mom, “Can you
come out-can you-can you come with me to the
uh—”
Trog: To the circus.
Wayne: “—to the parking lot and like help
me practice?” And
she was like, “Sure.” She was like, “Sure,”
and uh, so like I held onto her—I got
my gear on and I got in the parking lot, we-we-we
went into the big top, and so
I—
[Baaulp laughs]
Wayne: [Laughs] We-we went to the parking
lot, I grabbed her hand, and I started-and
I like, I maybe had her hold my hand for five
minutes
and I was just like, let go, and I don’t
know what happened, I just got it. And I was
just like doing everything. Like, everything
felt possible, like going at the max speed,
turning, braking, I could do every single
part of it and it felt fuckin’ crazy because
two days ago I was literally like—I felt
like death just trying to stay on the thing.
Baaulp: You saw like a wire and you started
going on that
and then someone—
Trog: Did you have a joy buzzer in your hand?
Baaulp: Yeah.
[Wayne laughs]
Baaulp: And then you went acr-and then you
went across the wire
effortlessly, but then midway through someone
tossed you like a giant metal rod—
Wayne: Mhmm. There was one time where I had
a hard time
braking so I shot the handkerchiefs out of
my mouth and used it to rope around
the light post to stop myself.
Trog: [Unintelligible].
Baaulp, laughing: [Crosstalk] Yeah.
[Baaulp and Wayne laugh]
Wayne: The, um, but yeah no, and then uh,
and then like I
tried it one more time the next day on my
way home, we-we stopped at a big
parking lot and I was-I tried like-I tried
some harder shit like going down and
uphill. Had some failures there, some success.
Uh, the-and then I got home from
my trip yesterday and took it out on the street
and then I just realized like,
I feel like my grasp on this is that of which
people have described they get after
like, multiple weeks of riding it. Like I
feel fully confident riding on it at
like full speeds, doing tight turns like without
any gear, which is dangerous
and scary and I’m not doing—Don’t worry,
people listening at home, don’t be
scared for me, I’m wearing gear when I’m
s’posed to.
Wayne: The uh, but like, like last night I-I-I
got in the Discord
call and I went for a joyride and I just rode
around my neighborhood on like a
bunch of like cracked, like pothole-y roads
and I could still-I could still
handle it. I’ve been… in love with this
thing. I road it all day today, that’s
pretty much all I did, I was out there for
maybe like three or four hours.
Baaulp: I think this is what people describe
as flow. Like, like it is-it has a term—
Wayne: Mhmm.
Baaulp: It’s called flow when like, that
feeling you get when like you’re trying
to get something—I only know about it because
of fighting games, but like—it is-it is
the same here, it’s like yeah, it just clicks
for you and you just get it. And you’re
just in the zone and uh—
Wayne: Yeah, absolutely.
Baaulp: And the-and the reason why you picked
it up in a few
days whereas some—uh, is because you’re
not old, your mind is young and fresh.
Wayne: I guess so. The forum that I use uh,
a large majority of its users are in their
like, fifties and it’s funny. It’s like-like
these people are not people I would be associating
with and like-like-a lot like—there are
a couple—there are a lot of like, you see
electric unicycle YouTubers um, like some
of my favorites like—one of my favorites
is this probably like late
twenties early thirties guy from China, he’s
really cool, he’s like amazing at it, he
does insane shit that I don’t think I’ll
be doing for like a long time. Uh, there’s
like another-there’s another guy from New
York who’s like probably
late twenties, uh, and then there’s-and
then you just-it just procedurally goes
up. My next favorite YouTuber is like, this-this
guy in his forties who’s like
a dad and his kids are in all of his videos,
and then you go even further and
like the absolute like, enthusiasts who are
like, ripping open their unicycles
and like, they know like about all the motherboards
and shit, and all the
intense intricate shit, they’re like fifty
and sixty and seventy. These old ass
men doing this shit.
Trog: There’s no way a seventy-year-old
is riding an
electric unicycle. They would die.
Wayne: They could do it! They could do it.
Like it-like it—I
think-I think like if you put your mind to
it, and you like trust yourself, I think
anyone could do it. Genuinely.
Gir: If you can think it, you can do it.
Wayne: Yeah. You-yeah. Prepare to mutate!
Prepare to mutate!
EUC! The [laughs]—
Baaulp: I’m not into this, but it does give
me hope that I’ll
be able to play fighting games as an old man
and then people-and then-and then
when I beat my grandkids with like the hardest
Kazuya combos in Tekken 70 they
might get fed up and—
[Wayne laughs]
Baaulp: They get fed up and-they get fed up
and hack my-hack
my life support.
Wayne: [Crosstalk] Tekken 70…
Trog: You’re going to the home!
Wayne: For Tekken 70—[laughs] Hack your
life support!
[Baaulp laughs]
Gir: Extend my life with a life hack—See!
A literal life hack!
Baaulp, laughing: It’s a life hack!
Wayne: They plug your keyboard into their
brain like
Cyberpunk and they stare at you and they think,
“Kill grandpa!” As they type in
the codes.
Gir, laughing: Gain six more months with this
life hack!
Wayne: Hey, if Tekken 70 is going to come
out in our
lifetime I think game sequels as a whole are
going to be very different, huh?
Like that’s not gonna happen.
Baaulp: No, I-I just pulled a number out of
my ass.
Wayne: I know, what the hell is Tekken 70
going to be like?
Trog: It’s a racing game.
Gir: You don’t know because all the characters
that’re
replacing the ones you know now don’t exist.
Log: It’s a game of thought and action.
Baaulp: Yeah. Just like fighting games now—Heyyy!
Gir: Heyyy! [Unintelligible]
Wayne: The only classic Tekken character that’s
left is Jack
70.
[Baaulp laughs]
Wayne: All the others—it’s a-it’s a
totally new cast, but
there is still Jack 70.
Trog: Jack 70, he’s here. Because he doesn’t
age! He’s a
robot! They just keep making new ones!
Wayne: Bro, what the fuck—what would Jack
70 look like? For
reference, if you guys don’t know, uh listeners
at home, what Jack is, there’s
a character that’s been in every Tekken
game, his name is Jack, he’s a big
robot, he’s a big, white dude that’s a
robot with like fucked up, crazy extend-o
arms and he’s been in every game but he
gets-he gets a new revision. Jack, Jack
2, Jack 3, Jack 4, Jack 5, Jack 6, Jack 7.
What is Jack 70? Like how do they keep—
Log: I think he’s gonna look like a nucleus
with plasma
tendrils.
Baaulp, laughing: Yeah.
[Wayne laughs]
Trog: He’s a clownlike individual.
Wayne: They lose his visage of a racist man,
he-he no longer
looks like a military guy, he’s like a fuckin’
monster.
[Baaulp laughs]
Wayne: I have one last thing to say about
the unicycle
before we move on.
Trog: [Crosstalk] Uh-huh uh-huh, talk-talk
more about your
unicycle.
Wayne: Uh, well, I’ve been practicing-I’ve
been practicing
the seltzer bottle bit while on the unicycle
and I got like a good few
people with it.
Gir: [Crosstalk] Uh-huh, wow that’s a very
crazy bit—
Trog: [Laughs]
Okay, hang on though, if you actually record
a video of you riding on an
electric unicycle and spraying—and like
drive-by spraying people with a seltzer
bottle, I will give you like, ten dollars.
[Baaulp and Wayne laugh]
Wayne: Oh man. It’d have to be someone I
know, though,
because I think-I think like, adding the unicycle
in there makes that like,
scarier for strangers.
Trog: But that’s why it’s funny.
Wayne: Gir—I was talking to-like I was-I
was in a call with Gir while I was on my joyride
last night and like, Gir was saying like,
“Yeah, you should bring like—” I feel
like you said for some reason that, “—you
should bring a bat.”
Trog: [Laughs] You should bring a bat?
Gir: Yeah-yeah, no ‘cause your-your gear
makes you look like
a Cyberpunk like, hell man.
Wayne: I look like—No, genuinely, when I’m
fully geared up, I look like a Hotline Miami
character like, I look like-like if I had
a bat I just would be. The-but yeah, I need
to be careful because like, I did last night
on
my—I want to talk about a few experiences
that I’ve had about riding the thing. I-so
I took it out on the roads for the first time
last night, and within the first twenty minutes
uh, I got stopped by a cop. Um, it happened
almost immediately uh, the, and it was a very
strange interaction. The like, chat—
Gir: Chat?
Wayne: I hate when I call them chat. Listeners
at home—it’s different with a podcast!
I’m-I’m never used to that. Listeners
at home, as you know, ACAB, fuck cops, the—So
like, pretty much when I interact with a cop
I do my best to just get out of it as soon
as possible, like I like, so when I was talking
to him, he comes up to me and he’s like,
“Hey buddy,” and I’m like, “Hey, how’s-how’s
it goin’,” and he’s like, “What is
that thing?” And I’m like, “It’s an
electric unicycle.” And he says, “Shouldn’t
you be riding that thing during the day?”
And I’m like, “No, I got a headlight,
I can see. There’s not that many cars out.”
And he’s like, “Aight, don’t-try not
to get hit by a car.”
Trog, laughing: Okay.
Gir, laughing: That’s a good trick.
Wayne: And I’m like, “O-okay, I’m gonna-I’ll
try that.”
The-and then I-I ride away, I ride away and
like, all the while, while that’s happening,
I’m in the Discord. I’m in our Discord
server with like Gir, Baaulp, a few
other people, Scorpy, the-and like Scorpy
the whole time is using our fucking YouTube
musicbot to play like, police siren noises
in my ears—
[Baaulp laughs]
Wayne: —Which is like, stressing me out
even more and I’m like, I drive away and
the first thing I’m like—I drive away
from the cop and the first thing I say is,
“Scorpy, fuck you. Fuck you, man.” The-uh,
I’m sure he got a laugh out of it. And then-so,
yeah—I drive another forty feet away or
somethin’ like that and then the cop turns
around and comes back, and-and he’s like,
“Hey, that thing’s pretty cool.” And
I’m like, “Yep, that’s why I bought
it.” And he said the dumbest thing, “It
has brakes and everything.”
Trog: Yeah, yeah.
Wayne: And I’m like, “Yeah, man.”
Gir: Yeah, I can stop. [Unintellgible]
[Baaulp laughs]
Wayne: You can-you don’t die when you accelerate
on this
thing.
Baaulp, laughing: Yeah?
Trog: He thought it was like the movie Speed
where if you go
under a certain miles per hour it’ll just
explode.
[Wayne laughs]
Baaulp: Dude, why isn’t that-why isn’t
that Speed 2. I wanna
Keanu Reeves on an electric unicycle that’s
going forty miles per hour, and if
it stops he blows up.
Gir: That doesn’t work though, ‘cause
he would jump off of the
fuckin’ thing and just let it explode fifty
feet down the street!
Trog: No, it follows you.
Baaulp: No! But then it blows up if you get
off!
Gir: Yeah, but it’ll explode fifty darn
feet down the street,
you’d jump off and you’d already be so
far away from it!
Wayne: Bro, it’s like-bro, it’s like a
bomb that could like
blow up a building, it would like, kill you
still.
Baaulp: [Crosstalk] Yeah.
Trog: [Crosstalk] Annihilate you.
Wayne: It doesn’t matter.
Gir: Uh, no, I would avoid it.
Wayne: I’d simply jump behind a barrel.
I’d get behind a
tree. So, uh, yeah, the rest of—other than
that-other than that encounter, the
rest of the joyride was like, super fun, and
it was like a very cool vibe to
just be riding around my town around like-around
like midnight with no one else
there just like, talking to my friends. Like,
the motorcycle helmet does a very
good job of insulating like, the audio. Like,
they heard me pretty well, I could
hear them perfectly.
Gir: And that’s where my point came in,
was-here’s this
man-I had even brought this up—Imagine you’re
walking down the street, it’s
like fucking midnight, you’re just out for
a night walk, and someone comes
riding down the street right next to you,
like right past you, dressed like a fucking
Hotline Miami character on a fucking electric
unicycle, and all you can hear as
they pass by is like, mumbling about random
shit.
[Trog laughs]
Wayne: I was like, “Man, nobody picks up
these sticks, who’s
pick-someone-picks up these sticks on the
sidewalk, we have no infrastructure,”
like—
[Baaulp laughs]
Trog, laughing: Just like a crazy person.
Wayne: Like-something-something like that
or like-or like, “Man,
Kirby Air Ride music is awesome,” was like
the other thing I was saying ‘cause
Gir was-I-Gir was like—
Gir: I kept playing Air Ride music.
Wayne: We-we were using the musicbot and I
was like, “Yo,
like, put on some-put on some music,” first
thing Scorpy does is he plays like,
the circu-the theme of the gladiators—
[Gir sings the beginning of Entry of the Gladiators]
Wayne: Fucking yeah, and I’m like, “No,
you fucking bitch,
don’t do that.”
[Baaulp laughs]
Trog: “Because I like it too much, and it’ll
distract me.”
Wayne: I was toolin’ around—I keep, for
some reason whenever
I’m talking about the unicycle I always
say, “tooling around,” I don’t know
why.
Trog: You’re turning into a fifty-year-old.
Wayne: The—
Trog: You’re aging.
Gir: It’s all these people—I don’t like
your new friends you
hang out with.
Wayne: [Laughs] I was tooling around in the
fuckin’-in the—
Log: I was knifin’ around.
Wayne: No, I don’t, I don’t have a single
friend on that forum.
I have-I have-there’s nice people, but I
wouldn’t call any of them my friends.
The uh, and yeah, I was toolin’ around in
this parking lot and Gir put on—Gir was
like, “Yo, I’m gonna put on fuckin’
Kirby Air Ride City Trial music,” and I
was
like, “Hell yeah,” fuckin’, I was ridin’
around listening to that shit, it was
awesome. And Gir was like, “I’m going
to get you killed by playing this music.”
[Gir and Baaulp laugh]
Wayne: Which is-which is fine, I’m already
skilled enough to
handle that thing at its top speed, which
like-I have a—it’s called a Gotway Mten3,
it is a-it’s the smallest electric unicycle.
Um, it’s not like bottom tier, like there
are some really shit old ones you can buy.
It’s pretty decent, its top speed is like—I
have the weaker version so it’s top speed
is like maybe
a little over sixteen miles per hour, um,
the—which on its own, when you’re just
standing on like a platform, that real-that
feels really fuckin’ fast. The wheels that
I’m gonna get in the coming months can go
like, thirty-five miles per hour which like,
I am both scared and can’t wait to experience
what the fuck that feels like.
Log: I think it’s irresponsible to have
like, a clown tool that can go that fast.
[Baaulp laughs]
Trog: But then how do clowns get to work?
Wayne: [Laughs] Bro, you know how fast a clown
car goes?
Log: They’re only allowed to drive that
in the circus arena.
[Baaulp laughs]
Wayne: Yo, first-first-first WayneRadioTV
electric unicycle
stream is I’m gonna-I’m gonna race four
clowns in a clown car with my electric
unicycle [laughs] the—
Baaulp: That should be the next uh-uh what
the fuck are
those movies called?
Log: Gremlins?
[Baaulp laughs]
Wayne, laughing: Gremlins. That should be
the next Gremlins
movie, man. A clown—
Gir: Don’t feed your clown after midnight.
Wayne: [Sighs] But yeah, that joyride was
really cool, um,
and then today I took it out and the like-this
thing I am ninety-nine percent certain
that I own the only one of these within like,
a hundred mile radius. Because
the looks I’ve got, and like the amount
of people who like, just point and me
and are like, “What the fuck is that?”
It happened so many times that I took it
out today. I had some dude on a motorcycle
like go out of his way to pull into the
parking lot I was in, drive up to me, and
be like, [in a southern accent] “What
the hell is that?”
Gir, in a southern accent: What the hell is
that thing?
Wayne: And I was like-and I was like-and I
like, I yelled at him over the-the roar of
the engine, “Electric unicycle!” “What?”
“Electric unicycle!” And he’s like,
“That’s pretty cool!” And I’m like,
“Yep!”
Trog: That-That’s what they say now, but
you’re going to get
into like a Frankenstein situation where people
start getting scared of you and
they-they like they think that you’re a
monster.
[Wayne laughs]
Trog: They’re going to chase you out of
town with torches
and pitchforks.
Wayne: I was thinking like, if I keep doing
late night
joyrides like, the cops are gonna know who
I am. I am going to be like a
regularly seen figure and like, I wonder if
I’m ever gonna get shit for it
eventually. The-like, I think it depends on
if I ever get complaints or
something like that. ‘Cause I’m not-I’m
not breaking any laws you fuckin’ cops!
Like—
Gir: No, but you look scary at night.
Wayne: I do look scary! I do look scary. I
do-I look cool
too, but—
Trog: Which is why you need to dress up like
a clown!
[Baaulp and Gir laugh]
Wayne: I would get so many more complaints
if I was
riding around on that thing in clown gear.
Trog: I’m not talking about like half-ass
clown gear, I’m
talking about full-ass parachute pants, giant
shoes, curly wig, red nose, face
paint clown.
Wayne: I think if I rode my electric unicycle
with clown
shoes I would die.
Trog: Then that’s your next step.
Wayne: I think that would get me killed. Like
[laughs]—
Trog: You have to learn.
Wayne: That’s-that’s day forty shit. I’m
on day five, leave
me alone. The uh-but like-I was walkin’
my dog, I walked past my neighbor who I’ve
never spoken to before, who like walked out
on their porch and was like, “I saw
you on your scooter thing! That was pretty
cool!” And I’m like, “Yo, thanks.”
Like I’m like, a little local celeb now.
[Gir and Baaulp laugh]
Wayne: It’s fuckin’-it’s fuckin’ hilarious.
And-and today,
I-I have a really funny little story. There’s
this one street that for whatever
reason, everyone who has a dog on it just
does not fence in their dog, and
every single one of the dogs is a little troublemaker,
like all of them. I’ve
seen so many just loose dogs on that street,
and it’s so hard to get them to go
back to where they need to. But, I rode down
that road this morning on my
electric unicycle, and I saw, just on the
sidewalk, just walking down perfectly
fine on the sidewalk, was just this little
Shih Tzu, totally unleashed, totally
unsupervised, and I was like, “Goddammit.”
And I was like-and as I pull up,
there’s this thought in my head like, “Should
I help it? Like should I go up? I
think I might know where this dog lives.”
And as I drive closer, I’m like, “Wait
a minute, I am the sheep dog for this dog.”
And I drive-I drive up to the dog,
and I literally start talking about it, like,
“Hey! Where are you supposed to
be?” And this little Shih Tzu like looks
up at me like, “What the fuck is that thing.
That’s a man on a wheel.”
[Baaulp laughs]
Wayne: And like it-it like-it immediately
like-it doesn’t
look like particularly like, terrified, but
it immediately just looks at me like,
turns tail and y’know that little dog trot
where they’re not like full-sprint
but they’re like, moving as fast as they
can without exerting too much energy?
Like, just trotting as fast as possible and
like, it like, I real-I remembered
where it probably lived and it was like running
around in the front yard and I
just kept zigzagging back and forth going
like, “You gotta go home! I’m not leavin’
till you go home!” And eventually it walked
around to the backyard and I saw it
go up to the porch and presumably through
their dog door. And I was like-I felt
so good I was like, “Yo, I just herded this
dog! I was a shepherd today! I’m
doing good with this!”
Wayne: And then when I went to the parking
lot later, the
same thing happened! Another dog got off its
leash, except this was a much
scarier place ‘cause the parking lot was
right next to a busy road. I didn’t
like, save that one myself but what I did
was I was like, I went up to them and
was like, “Are you good?” And what I did
was I like, I drove the unicycle like,
by the road and just kept going like up and
down the road as like a wall and the dog didn’t
approach me. So like, I am like-this like-weird,
high tech dog rescuer, I’m a public servant
now.
Log: Cyber-clown savior.
Trog: Hey, y’know, if the-if the streaming
thing
never—y’know, doesn’t pan out then…
you got an in.
Wayne, laughing: [Crosstalk] Cyber-clown savior.
Baaulp: Yeah, just uh, just never bring that
to like Boston,
‘cause then you’ll be known as like, ‘the
electric unicycle idiot,’ or
something.
Trog: [Laughs] The electric unicycle moron.
[Gir laughs]
Wayne: No matter what, it looks cool. The-the
like, there’s
like-there’s a huge community of people
riding these things in like, New York
City, I’m certain there’s a ton of people
in Boston that ride them—No, I know
there are, I watch a guy who’s from Boston.
The-I’m-you’ll probably see
someone one one day and like, it’ll probably
be the kind of thing where like,
you’re only seeing it now that someone’s
brought it up to you.
Gir: I will say, I live in a city that would
have something like that probably more than
a lot of other cities, never once in my life
have I seen somebody riding one of them.
Wayne: I’ve never seen one either, and like,
when I brought this up to my relatives who
were up on our trip, like, before they even
saw me get—before they even got to see me
ride it, they were like, “Yeah we just saw
a guy on one.” And I’m like, “No fuckin’
way!” I didn’t even know this thing existed
until a month ago! I didn’t know this was
a technology you could buy.
Baaulp: I’ve seen people ride all sorts
of things around the
city, and they always look uh, like they’re
wasting their time.
Trog: Yeah, as opposed to Baaulp who just
walks everywhere like a moron. Look at this
walkin’ idiot.
Wayne: What does that mean? This is a vehicle—this-this
is a
vehicle that is eco-friendly, that can take
you speeds at which at like-like
cruising speeds that would be good for a city.
Like, they’re amazing in city.
Baaulp: No, that’s just, uh—What, are
you too good to walk?
[Trog laughs]
Wayne: Yeah, it’s cool. It’s fun as fuck!
Trog: Baaulp is calling people out. If you
don’t walk
everywhere, Baaulp thinks you’re just a
dumb idiot.
[Baaulp makes a sound of agreement]
Wayne: The next steps on my electric unicycle
journey, I
gotta-I gotta-I gotta learn—I gotta practice
driving on like slightly busier
roads. Like tomorrow I’m thinking I’m
gonna try to go get coffee on it, um, the
uh, which’ll be a lotta fun. I gotta learn
how to ride backwards, um, y’know,
like that’s necessary for juggling.
[Baaulp laughs]
Trog: Yes, very important.
Wayne: Yeah, that’s so-that so far, I have
fallen off this thing, but I always end up
stumbling. I’ve never landed on my ass or
like my—I wear a ton of gear but I’ve
like yet to actually hurt myself. Uh, usually
what happens is like I’ll jump off and the
wheel will take a bigger hit than me. But
that little thing, it’s a trooper. It has
taken so much damage and it’s like, perfectly
fine. It’s all cosmetic damage. Um, the
uh, and then uh, the like final frontier is
like, jumping. I mean if you-if you modify
them by—
Trog: [Crosstalk] How do you jump?
Wayne: —So the-like—What you do is—They
call ‘em Kuji Pads,
‘cause there’s a guy on YouTube called
Kuji Rolls who like, invented them,
essentially. What they are is like-they’re
a-they’re like a thick layer of
neoprene padding that you put on the wheel,
right above like—not-not above your
toes but like the center of your foot, right
above that, and what it does is
like—it lets you get a grip on the wheel
that you wouldn’t otherwise have. So
like, you grip it, you-you ju—you buckle
your knees and you jump and you grab
that pad and you go up in the air and you
take the wheel with you. If you jump
off of it like, without a modded wheel, you
will just go up and your wheel will
keep going without you, and you will eat shit
and your wheel will explode.
Gir, laughing: Yeah, and you’ll die.
Wayne: But like, when you-when you do that,
it is such a
neat skill to have because it means that like,
if you want to like transition
from riding in the bike lane to riding on
the sidewalk, you don’t have to stop
and like, lift up the wheel, which is like
what I would have to do now unless
there’s a ramp, which is what I’ve been
using for the most part. Um, but like,
they’re doing crazy shit. The videos in
which he describes how to jump he’s like
jumping over like small manmade moats—It’s
like crazy how much distance they’re
getting. And the final thing that I will never,
ever do is riding down stairs.
That’s horrifying and I will be fine not
partaking.
Gir: Yeah that’s like asking for your neck
to be broken.
Wayne: Yeah, the—I’ve never seen anyone
fall doing it, but
that’s ‘cause the people who do it are
experts, but that’s just like—No, I’ll
just-I’ll just stop and go down the stairs.
I think I’m good.
Gir: Yeah, I was going to say, to round out
this-this… vehicle
talk, I will say one last addition before
we move onto the questions. I’ve been
thinking about just getting like-like a Razor.
Like a regular ass, basic,
non-motorized Razor scooter just to facilitate—
Trog: Hell yeah.
Gir: —going down to the corner store, ‘cause
for the next
two months I can’t renew my license.
Trog: Now is a Razor scooter—‘Cause whenever
I think about using
a scooter, it’s not really efficient in
terms of like—
Wayne: It’s not even remotely efficient.
Trog: —force exerted to like distance traveled
I feel like
is worse than just about any option.
Gir: No, distance traveled here is… the
distance I’m talking
about is far enough that walking sucks, but
not so far that it would be more exhausting
to use it.
Trog: May I make a suggestion?
Gir: No.
Wayne: My electric unicycle kick like, this-this-this
thing
that I’m doing, part of the reason why I’m
doing it is because I’ve always had
this desire to know how to rollerblade, but
rollerblades fuck me up more than
this electric unicycle thing even though the
electric unicycle is technically way
more dangerous. I—There’s-there’s a
video I saw a while back that like-that put
this bug in my brain like, “Man, one day
you need to get really good at
rollerblading,” where it was like, someone
rollerblading to literal Jet Set
Radio music and they jump on a fucking rail
and start grinding and I was like, “Holy
shit! That would be so cool to be like, a
master at that.” But like, I hate the
idea of not being able to just like, get rid
of the wheels off your feet and
just start walking, like, if you’re on a
rollerblade and like, something goes wrong,
your only option is to eat shit. You can’t
just like, save yourself.
Gir: And that-that’s what I was gonna bring
up. My—The route-the
path that I would be taking is exclusively
next to a busy road with a sidewalk
that is barely wider than I am. So, uh, eating
shit in that situation would be
uh, lethal.
Trog: Now—
Gir: A scooter reduces that immensely, even
more than if I
were to have a skateboard.
Trog: Now may I make a-now may I make an observation?
Uh—
Gir: Sure.
Trog, cracking up: I think you—the visual
of you riding a
child’s Razor scooter down to the corner
store as a full grown adult next to a
busy street—
Wayne, laughing: [Crosstalk] I can see—yeah—
Trog: —is probably the funniest thing I’ve
thought of in the
last hour and a half of recording.
Wayne: I don’t know if-I don’t know if
they make unmotorized
Razor scooters—
Trog, laughing: [Crosstalk] For adults.
Wayne: That like-that like are—Yeah, I don’t
think they make
those for adults.
[Trog laughs]
Wayne: I think you can only get an electric
scooter. Which
like-why not an electric scooter?
Gir: Those’re expensive.
Wayne: Like that-those are-those are cool.
Trog: Oh, Razor scooters for Tyler who’s
like in eighth grade!
[Wayne laughs]
Gir: Tyler won’t let me borrow his!
[Trog and Wayne laugh]
Baaulp: They’re-they’re expensive because
they’re adult sized,
Gir.
Gir: No, they’re not.
Trog: That is true.
Wayne: Mhmm.
Gir: They’re the exact same size I work
with a guy who had
one! It’s the exact same size…
Trog: [Crosstalk] I am all for Gir purchasing
a child’s scooter
and riding it to the corner store.
Gir: Whatever!
Wayne: I will-honestly, I’m gonna-I’m
gonna shill the EUCs
like, for the rest of my life to you guys,
probably. Like, you probably-you—Here’s
the thing, here’s the thing. Like, let’s
say I end up-we end up all moving to a
place where we’re pretty close together,
I’ll have that thing, you’ll be able
to see it, and I will want some of you to
try it, because it is like—
Gir: I’m on Razor’s website right now,
and here’s-they
filter—They filter ages—
[Wayne laughs]
Gir: Kids five to seven, and then they have
eight through
twelve—
[Baaulp laughs]
Wayne, laughing: Perfect!
Gir: —And then one specifically labeled
teens and adults.
[Wayne laughs]
Trog: Uh-huh.
Gir: Alright?
Trog: Like I said, I am all for this excursion,
I think you
should do it.
Gir: I’ll get one with the big wheels uh,
so I can put—I can
attach a cart on it so it sounds like it has
a motor.
Trog: Oh, yeah. [Laughs] That’ll be so much
fun.
[Gir laughs]
Trog: Can we all pick just like, a weird fucked
up mode of
transportation and-and all decide like, Wayne
can have-Wayne can have his
electric unicycle—
Wayne: [Crosstalk] We have the funniest gang.
Trog: —Gir can have a Razor scooter, I want
to ride two
hoverboards at the same time, but not one
on each foot, I want one for my feet
and one for my hands.
[Baaulp laughs]
Trog: So I’m like on all fours riding these
two fuckin’—I’m
like a dog on wheels.
Wayne: You are asking like—the injury you’re
gonna get there
is like, you’re gonna lose your balls, man.
Like, you’re gonna like, fall and
like it’s gonna stretch you out and you’re
gonna land balls first on the ground—
Baaulp: I want-I want to be like that guy
from Twisted Metal
where I’m between two giant tires [laughs]—
Trog: Yeah.
Wayne: Yes! Bro, no, for real. If there was
a community like
the EUC community but for being Axel or whatever
his name was from fuckin’
Twisted Metal, I would-I’d be on that. I’d
would be on that.
Trog: [Unintelligible crosstalk]
Log: Um, I just had like a genius idea that
I can’t execute ‘cause
I’m not an engineer. Uh, electric pole vault.
Gir, laughing: How—what?
Trog: What is that? How does that work?
Wayne: How? Wha—Explain.
Log: Alright, Okay, so like inste—So you
know pole? Um, at
one end you have a little wedge kind of thing
with a motor in it, right? So you-you
wedge that end into something, you activate
the motor and it pole vaults for
you.
Gir: That’s the dumbest thing I’ve ever
heard.
Wayne: But—Okay, okay, so how is that-how
is that a method
of transportation beyond just a single jump?
Like, can you-would you be able to
continue?
Log: [Crosstalk] You can continue-you can
continue and just
replace it.
Baaulp: Yeah.
Gir, laughing: This is the dumbest thing!
Wayne: Hold on, re-describe this to me. I
need to—
Baaulp: You’re basically just pole vaulting
like, over and
over again!
Log: Yeah, and that’s kind of—but imagine
this, like, you
can go—If it’s-if it’s an electric pole
vault then you can pole vault up.
[Baaulp laughs]
Trog: You can pole vault up without electricity,
though,
like the pole vault is used for the…
Wayne: The first thing you do is go up!
Gir: You’ve essentially described something
that’s as-as equally
like, pointless as electric stilts.
Trog: Electric stilts would be pretty fucking
sick, though.
I would totally use electric stilts.
Log: We were-we were asked to describe fucked
up means of
transportation, so, I-I don’t—
Gir: Well it-it still has to transport you,
though! [Laughs]
Log: It takes you from one place to another,
and I think it’s
fucked up. So, I think-I think that you should-you
should perish.
[Gir and Baaulp laugh]
Wayne: I feel like the-the visual-the visual
of this gang of people is like, you—Like,
my-my thing is like weird, but it is-but it’s
very practical. I would be just like, speeding
up way ahead of you guys then turning back
and seeing like, Gir like pushing off the
ground, Trog on the ground like, eating gravel
as he like rumbles down the road, like, oh
man.
[Gir laughs]
Trog: [Crosstalk] I don’t think I’m describing
mine good
enough.
Log: Hey, we’re basically creating the vehicles
for a Mario
Party battle mini-game.
[Wayne laughs]
Trog: Yeah, we’re like the coolest RPG team,
like we-like we
are the RPG characters. We all have our own
thing.
Baaulp: Also, I’m a little insulted because
Axel would be way faster than your electric
unicycle, the only—
Wayne: Actually, that’s true. No, you’d
have the-you’d have
the speed of a car, is the thing, like—
Baaulp: The only drawback is if I make any
mistakes the wheels keep going and my hands
get ripped off.
[Baaulp, Gir, and Trog laugh]
Wayne: Yeah, the thing is that like, there’s-there’s
that
downside, and also I believe there’s the-the
other downside that I believe that
character in lore is described as in excruciating
pain at all times because
that is a torture device.
[Baaulp laughs]
Trog: Well, that’s the price you gotta pay.
I wanna change
mine from the double hoverboard—I have posted
an image in the chat, the-the people
listening to this can’t see this, so I’m
going to try and describe this—Imagine
if your body was a giant rollerblade, just
covered in wheels from top to bottom,
that’s what I want to be. I just want to
be able to like, start running and
fall down and it doesn’t matter how I fall
because there will be wheels
underneath me that keep me going.
Wayne: Oh, yeah! I see what-like, that’s
a legit thing, though.
Like what is that?
Gir: That actually is pretty cool.
Trog: I don’t know.
Wayne: What do they call that?
Baaulp: There’s like a rollerblade suit.
Trog: Yeah. I want to be the rollerblade suit
guy, but I want it to be motorized so I just
like, I’m like a-I’m like a fuckin’
Transformer—
Wayne: That’d be dope.
Trog: —I curl up and roll out.
Wayne: That’s something that like, in a
Fast and Furious
movie, Vin Diesel would be attacked by when
he doesn’t have his car.
[Baaulp laughs]
Trog: Yeah, there’s like a group-there’s
like a squad of
these dudes that have like, miniguns on their
backs.
[Wayne laughs]
Gir: Y’know, I thought about it more-I’ve
sat and thought
about it, I think electric stilts would be
more like pneumatic stilts, where you
can like change your height at will.
Trog: That’d be cool. I’d be down.
Gir: That actually would be pretty practical,
yeah. It’s
like, “Oh, I gotta get over this really
tall fence, let me just shrink one leg
and extend the other, step right over.”
[Trog laughs]
Wayne: I’ve always wanted to try those like-like
we saw a
bunch of like, cosplayers using these when
we went to PAX East, they’re like pogo
stick stilts that like—
Gir: [Crosstalk] Yeah. Yeah, those are [unintelligible].
Wayne: —have like the bend of an animal’s
hindlegs, like-those
things look fun. Those things look like—I
would love to try those. They seem
like, not like—they’re thick, they’re
not like stilts which are literally just
like sticks, they look like they’re actually
like, pretty feasible to get on
and like, maneuver yourself around and bounce
around.
Gir: They’re what some prosthetics are—are
just those.
Trog: Yeah. I am looking at Amazon for jumping
stilts right
now, I think this is gonna be my new thing
that I get into, is these fucking
jumping stilts.
Wayne: No, no, if we-if we are-if we are rolling
around, if
we’re rolling around the streets of Texas
I’m on my EUC, you’re on your stilts,
Gir’s on his Razor scooter—
Trog: The thing is these stilts don’t make
you fast, I would
be slower on these, like this would be like—this
is essentially me like, riding
a pogo stick while you’re on a-like, in
a vehicle.
[Wayne laughs]
Gir: Can I say I chose this-this mode of transportation
to
get me like, five hundred feet away from my
house. I’m not about to roll around
town on this fuckin’ thing.
Trog: You should get a pogo stick. God, pogo
sticks are
expensive!
Wayne: Lame, lame!
Trog: This pogo stick is a hundred and fifty
dollars! And it’s
only for fourteen-year olds!
Baaulp: Sloane asks, “Podcast question—What
are each of your
favorite videos on YouTube that have under
one thousand views? Love, Sloane.”
Trog: Hmmm…
Wayne: Y’know, my memory’s horrible, but
I’m gonna go look in my playlist that is
specifically for stuff like this.
Baaulp: Yeah. Uh, new favorite-new favorite,
Buff dog. Um, that’s
a new-yeah, that’s a new one.
Trog: [Laughs] Buff dog.
Baaulp: It’s just a—this like, ten second
video of this buff Pitbull.
Wayne: Does that have less than a thousand
views?
Baaulp: Uh, let me check.
Wayne: You gotta-you gotta meet that criteria,
man.
Baaulp: For—At the time of this recording,
four hundred and
eighty-two views. It is a buff dog, and it
has some like, bass boosted Old MacDonald
like, Old MacDonald like, music over it.
Trog: Old MacDonald music, also known as the
song, Old MacDonald.
[Baaulp and Trog laugh]
Gir: This is a hard one, ‘cause most of
my favorite videos that
were under a thousand like, got popular after-after
the fact. So.
Trog: Yeah, y’know, I was looking for one,
and I was like, “Oh,
I know exactly which one I’d pick,” but
Green Goblin Sound Effects has like,
four thousand views.
Gir: Yeah, okay, that was I was gonna say,
is like, my pick-my
pick and, we’re going to have to ignore
that criteria because a lot of the time
these things just go over, but—
Baaulp: Yeah.
Gir: —my pick, three-point-five thousand
views after nine
years, ‘Ice Cube – “It Was a Good Day”
[HD] *extended version*.’
Trog: That’s a pretty good one.
Wayne: Guys. Guess what video has under a
thousand views. ‘zozo go bo ba bo ba.’
Trog: No, I don’t-that video doesn’t exist,
you are making
it up.
Wayne: It’s fuckin’ real! I’m lo-I’m
lookin’ at it!
Trog: No, it’s not.
[Baaulp laughs]
Trog: I don’t know what you’re looking
at, it’s not a real
video.
Wayne: Look! “Make a zombie go boom, boom,
boom, boom, boom.”
Trog: [Sighs] You can only watch that video
like, a hundred
more times and then it no longer qualifies
for this category.
Wayne: [Laughs] I know, it’s about to slip
out.
[Gir laughs]
Wayne: Ahhhh, you know what-a video that just
slipped out of
the ‘under one thousand views,’ chat,
is uh, “I stay committed while you
motherfuckers babysittin’,” that one has
over a thousand views, so that doesn’t
fall under the category here.
Trog: 'vxcv' has like, seven-seven thousand
views, like, I can’t
believe that 'vxcv' has [laughs] seven thousand
views.
Wayne: Yeah. 'vxcv'’s famous.
Log: Yeah, I’m-I’m really surprised 'this
video don't wach' has like, seven thousand.
Trog: No way. Really? All those people wachin’!
Wayne: That might be because of us.
Log: Yeah, maybe [laughs].
Trog: It’s probably because of us, nobody
else knew that fucking
video existed before we brought it up.
Gir: See, we do this to ourselves! Because
I feel like we find
videos that are like that, but then we show
other people and ruin it!
Trog: Yeah, hey, this sounds like a-this sounds
like
entrapment, you’re trying to get us to say
these so you can go watch ‘em and
put ‘em out of the category.
Gir: Yeah!
Wayne: It won’t r-it doesn’t ruin them,
though!
Trog: No, it doesn’t ruin them, I’m just
sayin’.
Wayne: Unless it becomes some big meme and
it’s blown out of
proportion, it’s fine. Like, how about around
a thousand. Like, just-just
like a very low view—
Log: I actually have a couple of killers that
are low view—well,
two specifically.
Wayne: Killers.
Log: ‘Alien Rap,’ and ‘Sad Song Featuring
Ging Gungus.’
Baaulp, laughing: Oh, yeah!
Gir, singing: “My dog died!”
Wayne: Wait is-is Alien Rap the one that’s
like-the one that’s
like, “Evoke the dark arts, the man is heap-sauce,”
that one?
Log: No, I can’t-I don’t-I don’t even
know how to find that,
Alien Rap is like the negative—the video
of the kid in negative like whisper
rapping with uh, like, a generic rock riff
playing over it.
Trog: Oh, yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Wayne: So the one that I was thinking about,
I actually have reuploaded on one of my channels
somewhere, where it was like a rap someone
made where the lyrics were just like, fucking
bizarre, I-the-the-the lyrics were like, “Spaceman,
evasive action, you better watch out, they’re
comin’ for ‘ya, they got a lot of fraction,”
And like, but the-the final-the final line-the
final bar is, “Mastered the Dark Arts, the
man is heap-sauce.” I’ll never forget
that last one.
Gir: I have to revise my answer because the
closest thing a
thousand, at 1.4K, and Holly will back me
up on this, is ‘Vegeta loves
a hot sauce feet.’
Trog: Oh, god.
Gir: That fucking cracks me up so fuckin’
bad.
Wayne: Wait, what is that? That sounds familiar.
Gir: It’s just like-like footage of Vegeta
with like that
fucked up weird fetish audio in the background,
like, “Oh, yeah, hot sauce on
these fuckin’ southern feet.”
[Wayne and Gir laugh]
Gir: And it gets me and Holly every fuckin’
time.
Baaulp: Oh damn, Zabz has like, hundred thousand
views, well
shit.
Wayne: Yeah, that video has some significance
that we don’t
understand.
Baaulp: It’s not for us.
Wayne: Actually no, maybe it-all the-all the
comments are… I-I
don’t know. ‘Cause some of the comments
are just a million emojis, which is pretty
typical of something like that.
Trog: ‘MyZaza’ has eleven thousand views.
Even ‘MyZaza’ isn’t safe.
Log: There’s one I can think of that, um,
did have around a
thousand views at one point but, due to our
meddling, shot way, way above that.
It’s uh, ‘Banjo Gyro!.’
Trog: ‘Banjo Gyro!’ was fuckin’ nothing
before we found it.
Log: Kevin—Yeah, Kevin, one of the moderators
in the
Discord, uh, Kevin-Kevin typed ‘Gyro’
into YouTube and found a—like a-like
a-just a CGI animation like, short film, called
‘Banjo Gyro!’, it’s the-like,
most absurd shit I’ve ever seen.
Wayne: It’s amazing. It’s incredible.
It’s so-it is fuckin’
awesome, and like, I feel like it has influenced
us in a lot of ways over the
years—The amazing aesthetic, just some of
the-some of the most memorable,
iconic—I feel like I can remember like-I
think my favorite part of ‘Banjo
Gyro’—sound design.
Baaulp: Yes, yes.
Wayne: Like I feel like I can remember every
weird little synth
noise like-like—[Wayne makes a sound similar
to a meow, followed by a low, repetitive noise].
Like, whenever someone moves, it’s not footsteps,
it’s like synth bubbling and like, just—It’s
so good. Every-every single noise sounds like
it could be used for like an alien abducting
you, like, it’s—Ahhh, it’s so good.
[Trog laughs]
Log: Yeah, it’s fantastic. So that has a
couple hundred
thousand views now, but it’s still fantastic,
so check it out.
Wayne: We-we found it aro—Yeah, we found
it around like-I
don’t even think it had like a hundred views
when he found it, and like we-we
found it, and we shared it around a little
bit, and it got a little boost, and
then from there it got shared around a little
bit. Back then when we found it,
none of us were even remotely popular. Yeah,
it was-it was like around—yeah.
Trog: We were all children.
Gir: Basically.
Trog: Practically.
Wayne: Real quick, I thought of one last one,
and I’ve shown it on like movie nights and
shit, it’s one of my favorite videos. It’s
literally titled, ‘MOV 3974 MOV’ like
.mov, and it’s a video of like, some dude
in his car like, saying like, “Yo, we drove
out here, the middle of nowhere, you better
give us all—you better give us your money
or this baby gets it!” And he’s in his
car with like his dog, wearing like a ski
mask, and he just pulls out like a little
plastic figure of a-of a fetus it’s just—I
can’t describe the video I’d have to-I’d
have to link it to you. We should probably
gather links for these videos so we can like,
put them in the description so
people can watch them.
Trog: This is a question from Gwimble, who
says, “What is
the absolute hardest a joke you’ve made
flopped, either in its terribleness or
its overall effort-to-enjoyment ratio? On
the flipside, what’s the lowest
effort joke you’ve done that’s gotten
the biggest reaction?”
Gir: I want to come out right—
Wayne: [Crosstalk] That’s a good question.
Gir: Come swingin’ right outta the gates
here, uh, in recent
memory, the worst—I don’t even remember
what the joke was, it was that bad, but
then uh, Wayne like let out—It was when
you let out like the most pathetic
like, fake laugh, and I was like, “That
wasn’t-that wasn’t funny, you didn’t
have to laugh.”
Wayne: Yeah, I don’t even remember what
he said, it was-it
was so just like-it was so pr—It was just
the kind of thing that like, he
didn’t even put like, much thought into,
he just kind of said it—
Gir: It was just something I said in passing,
and then you
were like, “Hahaha.”
Wayne: Just kind of a passing like, punny
kind of joke, and
like, and I was—I think I was playing Fall
Guys and I heard that and I was
like, in my head I was like, “Well, that
sucks,” and I was like—I wasn’t gonna
laugh or anything, but for some reason I was
so focused on the game I just went
like, “Ha…haha…” I just made like-the
most like antagonistic, pathetic laugh,
and Gir was like, “Eh, you know you didn’t
have to laugh.” Like it was just
[laughs].
[Trog laughs]
Baaulp: Ah, geez.
Gir: And conversely, the lowest effort thing
that got-that
got a lot of laughter was when we were in
Texas and it was like me, Wayne, Log,
and Lauren in the car, and I just pointed
at somebody and was like, “Hey, we
should run that guy over [laughs].”
Wayne: No, you said—You pointed at him and
said, “We should
kill that guy.” Just like—
[Trog laughs]
Gir: Yeah, I was like, “We should just kill
that guy.”
Wayne: It was [laughs] I don’t even think
we were in a car,
we were just walking around and you said that
and—
Gir: No, we were in the car! We were in the
car! That’s why
the first thing I said was run him over!
Wayne: That’s probably why not everyone
knows it, because we
were split into two groups at the time.
Baaulp: Yeah, I missed that on that.
Gir: But you guys like fuckin’ lost it and
I was like, “Why?
I just said we should kill a guy, that’s
all.”
Wayne: Ahh, this is a hard one for me.
Baaulp: I can’t remember the last time I
fell flat with a
high effort joke, I try—My brain probably
blocks that shit out.
Trog: Yeah.
Wayne: Traumatizing.
Baaulp: Man, I-I’ve gotten to the point
where I’m such good
friends with you all I know all the-I know
all the low effort buttons I can-I
can push.
Wayne: Yeah.
Baaulp: The low—Like, uh, this isn’t—
Wayne: Oh, [claps] I have your answer.
Baaulp: You have my answer, what is it?
Wayne: The—For-for-for Baaulp’s low effort
joke that got the biggest reaction, there
was like, I cannot remember for the life of
me what the conversation was about, but I
was there, Mira was there, maybe a few other
people were there, but Mira and I remember
this very vividly, and we were having some
conversation about like, playgrounds or something
like that, and Baaulp just said, in the stupidest
voice, it just came out of nowhere and made
no fuckin’ sense relative to what we were
talking about—
Baaulp: [Crosstalk] Oh, yeah.
Wayne: Baaulp just said, like, “Hey, I’ve
got some uh,
important monkey bars, here.”
Gir, laughing: [Crosstalk] I forgot about
that!
Wayne: And like, it made Mira and I laugh
so hard we almost
passed out. We were like, crying, like it
was-I don’t—The fucked up thing is
like, to everyone listening, everyone’s
just like, “What are you—Why?” Like,
and I could not tell you. Like it was just—just
a ‘you had to be there’ kind of
thing—
Gir: [Crosstalk] In the moment, yeah.
Wayne: It was in the moment, I don’t even
remember the
context, but I will never forget it. It was
just so dumb and out
of nowhere, it killed us.
Gir: I-I very vividly remember Mira gasping
for air.
Trog: I can’t think of it, I-I feel like
it’s almost like a
fear of mine, where it’s like, I feel like—‘Cause
I was thinking of this
question in terms of like, stream stuff that
we’ve done?
Wayne: Yeah, I mean, for the high effort stuff
that
definitely would be where that would come
up into play.
Trog: Maybe I’m gonna jinx us here, we’re
gonna have a real stinker here in the future,
but it’s like, I feel like everything that
we’ve put like, a lot of effort into, I
can’t really think of anything that’s
like, flopped. Like nothing, nothing that’s
flopped like hard, where it’s like, “Oh,
nobody thought that this was funny.”
Wayne: [Crosstalk] Yeah—
Baaulp: Well I mean, the thing is like, we
usually have a
good grasp on it, like, we don’t just throw
shit out there, we usually run it
by with each other, and that means that if
it isn’t funny it never gets in.
Trog: I suppose.
Baaulp: Like, we’re pretty good about that.
Trog: I can think of like, technical fuck
ups that have
happened, but nothing that’s like, been—
Wayne: Usually that makes things funnier.
Trog: Yeah, that’s true.
Wayne: I’m like, trying to think of like,
earlier streams
like, I feel like pre-Gub Gar I didn’t do
a whole lot of like, crazy stuff
like, on-with my Twitch channel.
Trog: [Crosstalk] Well, Gub Gar was the first
like, big stream that I can think of.
Wayne: That was-that was like, six months
in, and it was
like the first like big, higher concept joke
that I did. The uh—
Trog: Culmination of an ARG.
Wayne: I’m trying to think if there’s
anything—I feel like, like
I’ve had more things happen that are like
higher effort that don’t get a lot of
attention, less so than like, things like
hitting—
Trog: Right, yeah.
Wayne: ‘Cause like-like some things I look-I
look upon very
fondly, like G-33 Babel Initiative, which
is a stream where I got a gorilla
costume—
Trog: Oh, yeah.
Wayne: And we set up an-we set up an OBS scene
where Trog
and Baaulp were behind glass and were scientists
examining a gorilla playing
video games. It was a pretty weird concept
that was a little hard to pull off,
I think it was pretty funny, but it was-it
was like—it definitely was not as
well executed as it could have been because
like, I don’t think I gave a very
clear idea to Trog and Baaulp as to what I
wanted you guys to do, so like—
Trog: Yeah. You know what, legitimately, I
forgot about that stream, so I think that’s
my answer. Like, that-that stream it wasn’t
like a flop-flop, but it was like—It’s
literally like out of all the—
Wayne: [Crosstalk] It had some very funny
moments.
Trog: —out of all the bit streams that we
did, that’s the
only one I literally didn’t remember being
a part of until Wayne just brought it
up. It has to be my answer.
Wayne: [Laughs] I thought that one like, it
was good, it
probably could have been workshopped more,
like we probably coulda put more
time like—
Trog: I think you’re right. Me and Baaulp
just didn’t really
have a lot of direction, you had an idea of
like, “Alright, we’re gonna have me
in a gorilla costume, playing like, fucking
Apex Legend,” and I was like,
“That’s kind of funny in concept, but
what am I supposed to do?” And it’s like,
“Oh, I don’t know, just like talk about
it.” Like, “Alright.”
Gir: Oh yeah, I was a part of that, too.
Log: Oh, yeah.
Wayne: No, you weren’t.
Gir: Yeah, I was!
[Wayne laughs hard]
Wayne: No, you weren’t! How were you a part
of it? Oh wait
no, you and-you and-you—Log, I forgot about
Log and—See, I’m forgetting things
too. Log and Gir played Apex Legends with
me as the gorilla, which I also
thought was a pretty funny idea.
Gir: Literally the only time in my life I’ve
played Apex
Legends.
Wayne: So, I had a pretty clear idea in my
head of like, what I wanted it to be, and
like I had this idea in my head of how Trog
and Baaulp were gonna act, but like, I didn’t
want to be too directive, so I didn’t say
anything and then like, and then it just ended
up like, I was just sittin’ there slappin’
the controller and they were just like, “What
do we, like, what do we say about this.”
Trog: Yeah, it’s like, we definitely needed
more stage
direction, I was like, “I’m not sure what
direction I need to take this in.”
Wayne: I should have been a little bit more-a
little bit
more commanding with that. But it had-it had
some-some very fun- funny moments
like, such as like, the controller kept unplugging,
and like there were a lot
of good funny moments with like, you guys
talking about me like, “Oh, he-he
unplugged the fucking controller again, he
keeps unplugging the USB,” The uh-the
like, the funniest thing that happened—
Trog: Pulley system with a banana, I remember
that.
Wayne: Oh, yeah! That was like, I-that was
like the one-one
other gag I had in mind which was like, I
fastened a hook to my ceiling, which
is still there, I’m looking at it right
now, and I tied a banana around a very
fine, like—
[Trog laughs]
Wayne: —surprisingly sharp thread, and like-and
like hooked
it up like, to a—
[Baaulp laughs]
Wayne: I’m sorry, but with-with this app
I can hear every
little noise Baaulp makes, and I—Apparently
Baaulp like, charges his laughs,
like—
[Trog laughs]
Baaulp: Yeah, I do.
Wayne: [Laughs] Like, you-it might not come
through the
final recording, but like, when I-when I know
something is funny to Baaulp,
this is not something I hear in person or
in Discord, this mic here is just
more sensitive—I just hear him go like,
[Wayne imitates a slide whistle going
up in tone]—
Trog, laughing: He’s charging it, dude!
[Log laughs]
Wayne, laughing: He’s just like getting
ready to laugh!
Trog: He’s chargin’ it!
Wayne: [Laughs] And it totally ruined me.
So like, yeah, I
tied a banana to a thread, and I hooked it
to my ceiling, and I like, fastened
the hook on a heavy object, and like, at some
point during the stream I was
like, “Alright, I want you guys to give
me like positive reinforcement, like,
drop a banana into my cell,” and like, at
some point they did that, and like, I
was the only one, I’m only the-the only
one at my place for like physical help
ever, so when you said that, I had to like
stick my leg off camera and like,
kick the book so the banana fell and like
[laughs] and the banana—It’s crazy
how quickly a banana gets gross—
[Trog laughs]
Wayne: —once it’s like, open. Like, ‘cause
by tying the
thread, it squeezed the banana and caused
an opening, so the banana that was
perfectly fine like, the hour or two before
the joke actually happened, when I
set it up, came down a gnarly, and black,
and disgusting.
Trog: Ew.
[Baaulp makes sounds of disgust while Log
laughs]
Trog: Yeah, alright. That’s definitely the
answer.
Wayne: [Crosstalk] Like, it was bad. It was
fuckin’ bad, and
I think like--
Trog: And I legitimately forgot I was—that
that even happened. Like, gave me a brain
blast.
Wayne: [Laughs] It’s on the vods channel,
if you’re hearing
this and you’re curious, it’s still a
good watch even if it was kind of messy.
The funniest thing that happened in the stream
though, was uh, I was using a DS4
controller hooked up to my computer, for some
reason, back—I don’t know if this
is still a thing, but back then the native
input when you press the PS button
on a DS4 controller, it commands media programs.
For whatever reason, if you
start-if you have like a MP3 player open or
something like that, it will-it’ll
start playing a sound. And for that stream,
I-I had foobar open, which is my
media player of choice, it’s very bare bones,
very simple, but I didn’t have my
music open, I had my sound effects tab open,
and at the time I was doing—I had
previously done a joke involving Sora in Kingdom
Hearts 2, so I accidentally hit
the PS button and we’re doing this bit,
and all of a sudden you just hear Sora
go, “[Inhale] Donald! Goofy! Hyah! Neuh!
Fire!”
Gir: [Crosstalk] “Aladdin!”
[Baaulp laughs]
Wayne: Like, “Aladdin!” [Laughs] And I’m
like, I like-my
jaw, in the gorilla costume, just dropped
and I started laughing so hard I was
crying and we had this like, and you guys-I
don’t think you guys could hear it—
Trog: No, we couldn’t.
Wayne: So like, all of a sudden-all of a sudden
I’m just
like, sobbing and we had this signal where
if I put my hands on my head that
means you need to cut to break because I couldn’t
talk, because I was a
gorilla, and like, they’re like, “I think
the monkey’s crying.” Like it was
just—
[Log and Baaulp laugh]
Wayne: It was such a good moment.
Trog: It was so weird, yeah, because neither
me nor Baaulp
had stream audio, so we didn’t know what
the fuck—so we just like, didn’t react
to this bizarre scenario that just happened
because we had no context.
[Baaulp and Wayne laugh]
Trog: We-we-we—That was some sloppy production
on our part,
we-we’ve cleaned it up since then.
Gir: [Crosstalk] Learned from growing pains.
Baaulp: That was the early days.
Wayne: That was also like, I was still—I’m
always figuring
out the kinks in my fucked up greenscreen
set up, and like, that one—
Trog: [Crosstalk] Oh, yeah, that shit’s
[unintelligible].
Gir: [Crosstalk] Oh, you fucked it up every
single time.
Wayne: I had it like—there-there was like,
I was sitting on
the floor, so that’s extra prone to fuck
ups. I had the green screen like—there
was a nail in my wall that like a painting
used to be hung on, I had the
greenscreen like, pushed into that and then
clothesline clipped onto that, it
was the worst set up. I’ve now figured out
that I literally just use duct tape
and I tape it to the ceiling, that’s more
effective. But, the fuckin’ like—I
would just like sit wrong and all of a sudden
the greenscreen would fall and
you would just see this pile of boxes in the
corner of my room and you guys
were just like, “The gorilla has opened
up a hole in the void.”
Trog: “There’s been a-a breach.” It’s
funny in hindsight.
During the actual performance, it probably
could have been funnier. But it’s
funny to think about how fucked up it was.
Wayne: Yeah.
Log: I don’t know like, all of my-all of
my high effort
stuff is just uh, Gather Ye Power.
Gir: Hard to tell if any of the jokes land
or not in that
sense.
Wayne: Yeah, you don’t get that immediate
feedback, but I
think your humor in that lands. There’s
definitely some stuff that genuinely made
me laugh out loud.
Log: And I mean like, it’s not like I have
that big of a
viewership in the first place, so if anybody
goes out of their way to talk about
anything in that, that’s like-that’s like
shocking.
Wayne: I think a joke—I just want to compliment
you, I think
a joke in Gather Ye Power that still sticks
with me-I might be—I might be
miswording it, but it was like, one of your
side characters saying, “I’ll make you
wish the circus was never born!” Or something
like that.
Log: That was the main character. That was
Cube himself.
Wayne: Cube said that? Yeah, well, I remember
the line, not
who said it.
Log: [Laughs] So, that-that one was good,
I felt good about
that one, but one that I was like, for whatever
reason I thought, “People will
like this one a lot,” because I like this
one a lot, um, I had just like a
guardsman just standing in front of a-of like
a cart with-filled with bags of
money, and he was counting, so he was counting
like, “Nineteen, twenty,
twenty-one, those are my three favorite numbers.
And there’s twelve bags of
money in the cart.”
Gir: Okay, yeah, I remember that gag. That’s
a-that was a
good one.
Log: I thought, “Oh, that’s perfect.”
But yeah, nobody
really said anything about that one, so I
don’t know.
[Wayne laughs]
Baaulp: What you’re gonna have to learn
is that the subtle
stuff always goes past people’s heads.
Wayne: But it like-even if it doesn’t make
people like laugh
out loud and be like, ‘ah, that part was
so funny,’ like, if it’s subtle it
adds to like-it’s just-it’s this procedural
like-you’re just stacking up,
you’re gaining this long term charm like,
that people will look back on and be like,
‘yeah, it’s a very charming comic,’
even if certain things didn’t get the gut
busts goin’.
Log: Perhaps, I don’t think anything has
been like a flop,
though.
Trog: That’s what I’m saying, that’s
where my anxieties lie.
I feel like we’re overdue.
Baaulp: Naaaah, naaaaah.
Wayne: Oh well. We’d recover. I’ve had
flop streams, but
that’s not the same, like—
Log: I think the best return on investment
was playing as
Joni in your um, AI Adventure Call.
Wayne: Ahh, that was great. Yeah, that was
like—
Log: I didn’t have to try very hard at all
for that one
[laughs].
Wayne: You knew-you knew exactly what you
were doing, and we
gave you the right prompt. The fuckin’ sheep
shearing quest.
Log: The stars aligned for that one, it was
perfect.
Baaulp: This question is from Wowwywowwow,
they ask, and-and
like, the first half I can just answer, ‘cause
this-I already know the answer,
but there’s an interesting second half that
we can kind of expand on. “Did any
of you have any theatrical training prior
to becoming streamers/before getting
into Twitch? If so, are there any fun theatre
games you wish were-uh, you wish
were possible to practice at the moment?”
So, the answer is no, I-I don’t like—
Wayne: Theatre games? What’s a theatre game?
[Laughs] I’m
not a theatre kid.
Baaulp: Kind of like games that you would…
kind of play with
other performers to like, get in the mood
of like, doing improv or like acting.
I—Do any of us have theatre experience?
The answer is no, right?
Log: I did theatre in high school.
Gir: I-I was gonna say, Log and Holly did.
Trog: I was in theatre in middle school.
Baaulp: Yeah, but like, for me, no, I don’t
think Wayne—Like, Wayne,
did you have any?
Wayne: I have never done anything like that.
And-and that’s the thing, getting into this,
getting into streaming, like, that side of
things was not something that I ever thought
I was gonna evoke, I’ve never considered
myself in the past to be like, a good actor,
and never thought that was something that
I was gonna like pursue. But then as it went
on, that ended up being a huge part of it,
and like, and it turns out we’re all pretty
g—okay at it. Like, I wouldn’t say we’re
all like amazing actors or anything, but
like—
Baaulp: I think to expand on that quest—that
second half of
that question, like are there any games that
you play, like—
Gir: I can answer that one, because I never
got into theatre
‘cause I was too shy of a kid back then,
but because of all the Whose Line I
watched, there were so many things that they
would do on Whose Line that I wish
that I had friends would do that with me.
Baaulp: I mean, here’s the thing—
Wayne: That’d be fun.
Baaulp: We do kind of do it-like, what I was
gonna say was,
we do kind of do our own version of that,
where like-like yeah, we don’t do
theatre, but when it comes to comedy like,
aren’t we just like—as a group of
friends, aren’t we just always trying to
make each other fuckin’ laugh, though?
Like—
Wayne: It’s improv without it being like,
forced and
annoying, because it’s just like, what we
do. The like—
Baaulp: We are like the evil Shaolin—we
are like the evil
Shaolin monk, lotus temple monastery of comedy,
like—
Gir, laughing: What?
Trog: [Unintelligible]
[Wayne laughs]
Baaulp: We are always tryin’ to make each
other laugh, it is
always on sight, like, there’s no-no rules
it’s like, “Oh, I’mma-I’mma
try-I’mma try to make them laugh today.”
Wayne: “Oh, Wayne just got stopped by the
cops? Let me play
policesiren.mp3 in the group chat.”
[Trog and Gir laugh]
Baaulp: Yeah!
Trog: That’s hilarious.
Wayne: Like the fuckin’-it is-it is literally
nonstop
twenty-four seven, anytime we are with each
other that’s what’s happening.
Gir: I guess that’s true, ‘cause like
when you would be
driving home from work and I would play the
fuckin audio clip I designed of you
being like, “Oh, my name is Wayne, oh shit!”
And then a car crash—
[Baaulp laughs]
Wayne: “OH SHIT!” Yeah, the fuckin’—and
like, it really, it
is the equivalent of like, Shaolin monks of
the temple like, making their
children like, hang from tree branches by
their toes and like, and how the
adults developing iron egg skill like, just
constantly like putting themselves
through these fucking trials and tribulations.
[Trog laughs]
Baaulp: Like, we don’t play any like, explicit
like—we don’t
do any routines, but like, we-we-we know how
to make each other laugh, and
we’re good at like being very snappy because
like, we are just constantly,
like, every—even the people who aren’t
usually like, appear on streams, we are
constantly just trying to make each other
laugh, it’s like, kind of, it’s
uni—it’s special. Let me—I think so.
Gir: I would like to sit us down one day and
do a handful of
things like that, like-like one of the like-uhh,
I’m trying to think of the
name of it, where it’s like-like where everybody
says one word to form a
sentence, and you go back and forth between
like two people.
Trog: Oh, god. Just real theatre class shit.
Wayne: We did that. I mean, that actually—I
always thought
that was fun, but like, we did that, there’s
a JackBox game that was just that,
Word Spud, like in the first JackBox game,
and it was very fun.
Log: I’m thinkin’, I just think back to
the type of games
that we would play whenever we’re doin’
um, basically any production in high
school. And really like, all that stuff was
just to um, help you get into sync
with other people and uh, break the ice, I
guess. But it’s just not really
necessary for this group, I’d say.
Gir: Yeah no, icebreaker ones, no. ‘Cause
we’re already—the
ice-there’s no ice to be broken.
Wayne: I already know these people like a
book I’ve read a
thousand times.
Trog: It’s really the fact that any time
we do any of the
like, big production things, or even the smaller
stuff, just anything that’s
like a concept, we don’t write. Like, we
don’t-we just don’t. We-we are not in
the habit of writing anything down, basically.
Wayne: I think-I think-I think another thing
that like, I
like about us when I said that we were like,
okay at acting, like we ended up
being okay at that, I feel like the fact that
we’re not perfect adds to it a
lot, because we all—something that we all
as a group think is very funny, fuck
ups.
Trog: Yeah.
Wayne: When things go wrong, it’s fucking
hilarious. And
like, and like that can be a technical difficulty,
or it can just be someone
like saying something wrong, or just like
not knowing what to say, like we
thrive on each other’s like, failure.
Baaulp: Yeah.
Trog: But I’m saying that in the-in the-in
the fact that
it’s like-like we don’t do improv games,
we just like… technically like, almost
any concept stream we do is improv just by
the fact of like, well we’re not
gonna take the time to write down jokes beforehand,
we’re just gonna come up
with them on the spot. That is just technically
improv.
Wayne: Mhmm. You forge it-you forge them in
fire like, it’s
funnier, like than if you pre-write it.
Baaulp: Well we do do—what the plan that
we do use is that
we usually give ourselves a good jumping-we
give ourselves a good, yeah, jumping
off point to like, facilitate it, and we just
kind of like, hit the ground running.
Trog: Like for instance with the GameClam
thing like, we-we
like—Scorpy wrote up, ‘cause he directed
that one, Scorpy like, had a Google
Docs that just had an outline of like, “Alright,
Wayne’s gonna talk about this, then we’re
gonna play these videos, then Wayne’s gonna
talk about this,” and we talked about jokes,
like the day of beforehand, but we didn’t
like, wr—like nobody was ever reading off
of a script or anything like that.
Wayne: The one script in AI-dventure Call
that I had was
like, I prewrote the little limerick I said
at the intro ‘cause I can’t come up
with something like that on the spot, and
if I do it’ll be like really bad
[laughs].
Gir: And you know what, there was one time
Scorpy made
something where Wayne was reading a script
and Wayne fucking up was added into
the final product [unintelligible].
Trog: Oh yeah, that’s right. That doesn’t
really count, Gir,
that wasn’t a stream, that was for a project.
Gir: No, that was—but you know what I’m
sayin’.
Wayne: Yeah, Scorpy’s projects are pre-written
but that’s a
totally different thing, like—
Gir: Scorpy’s the only one of us that will
write things.
Like, at all.
Baaulp: That really says that like, “Hey,
here’s a
pre-written thing,” and he added a fuck
up to it, and it made it so much better
[laughs].
Gir: Yeah, [unintelligible].
Wayne: Yeah.
Baaulp: You don’t need to break the ice
if you are—have already
been friends for more than a decade.
Wayne: So I have a-I have another question
real
quick. This one’s an easy one, well, it’s
not so much an easy one as it’s like,
more on the jokey side, but it got me thinking
as soon as I read it.
Jimmiefingers in our Discord asks, “How
do you feel about ‘Best-By’ dates on
food?” And I read that and I was like, I
mean it’s important, right?
Gir: [Unintelligible].
Trog: [Crosstalk] Mhmm.
Wayne: But they make me mad. They make me
mad because like,
if-if I have food that is past the best-by
date, like, I will sit there and like,
just fucking like introspect for like, three
minutes, staring at the food,
smelling it, inspecting it, and just being
like, “[Sharp inhale] I—can I—I don’t—Can
I eat this? Like, it’s like two days past
the thing,” like it just, it annoys
me. I wish there was like a better way.
Gir: You have to have some logic about it.
There’s certain
things that you would know after a while.
Wayne: Yeah.
Gir: Like if it’s-if a date on there says
that it expires at that time, for certain
things, yeah, immediately just fucking get
rid of it. Other things, that thing’s probably
still good for another month.
Wayne: It-it makes-it makes me mad sometimes
with like meat,
like-like lunch meat. Like sometimes it’ll
be-it’ll be like past the expiration
date, but like, it like smells fine—Like-like
the give-the give with meat
sometimes is not the smell, but it’s like,
if there’s like slime. Like if
you—
Gir: [Crosstalk] The texture, if it’s slimy.
Yeah, ‘cause lunch meat
I feel like always smells like farts regardless,
so.
Wayne: The thing is is like, the slime test
fucks me up, because
sometimes lunch meat is slimy from the start.
Not like super slimy, but like a little
bit slippery, like it’s just a little bit
wet. Like if you buy deli cut like,
cold cuts, you get some of that. There’s
a-there’s a point where it’s obvious,
there’s a point where it’s obvious and
you need to throw it away. If it’s like
congealed,
you need to just fuckin’ get rid of that
shit.
Trog: I think I take the opposite approach
as you, Wayne, in which I find the best-by
date a comforting reminder of like, I-I get
anxious when it’s before the best-by day,
but like close, and then like once it hits
the best-by date I’m like, “Alright, cool,
it’s done.” I-I take this as law, so that
I don’t have to have that moral conundrum
of like, “Should I throw this out?” It’s
like, “Oh, it’s past the date? It doesn’t
matter I’m not gonna
check I’m just gonna throw it away.” It’s-it’s
out of my hands, Father Time has taken this
pack of ham from me.
Wayne: I mean, does that motivate you? Does
that motivate
you to be less wasteful and not buy food that
you’re not gonna eat?
Trog: Oh, hell no.
[Baaulp laughs]
Wayne: What the fuck, man? You gotta be better.
Trog: No, it makes me feel worse actually,
‘cause then I-I’m
like, I check my fridge it’s like, “Ah
shit, I gotta throw all this shit away,
I didn’t-I didn’t eat this—Why did I
think it was a good idea to buy three
cartons of eggs? When was I ever gonna eat
this?”
Baaulp: Three cartons of eggs? Damn.
Wayne: You go to the grocery store and it’s
like, “Oh yeah,
I’ll need all this stuff, and I’ll make
so many cool meals,” but then it just comes
around to it and it didn’t happen, and then
you just have—
Trog: [Crosstalk] And it just doesn’t happen,
and then you go order burritos again.
Gir: Yeah, that’s every time I buy food.
I will buy like, so
much shit-I’ll buy so much shit and then
like, an hour after I’ve put it away I
forgot that I just got it.
Wayne: It happens to me especially, like,
‘cause I still don’t
have my own place, I’m barred by the pandemic
from having one at the moment,
like-where like I’ll buy things to make
my own dinner, and like, then like the days
where I want to make it, like someone else
is using the kitchen and I like, don’t—
Gir: Yeah!
Wayne: There’s nothing more that I hate
than trying to use
the kitchen at the same time as someone else.
Gir: That’s exactly why I rarely cook for
myself, is I’m in
the exact same situation, it’s like, “Oh,
today I wanna make like that jambalaya,
yeah,” I’ll go out there and every-like
all the dishes are dirty already, there’s
somebody out there already making something,
it’s like, “Oh, I guess I’ll uh,
guess I’m eating ramen.”
Wayne: Can’t wait to have my own kitchen.
Oh, you know I’m gonna do the craziest shit
in there.
Log: The problem I have is I’ll get something,
I’ll put in
the freezer, I’ll determine, “Okay, today’s
the day that I’m gonna use this,”
so the day—the night before I take it out
of the freezer, put it in the fridge.
And then, that day I take it out and it’s
still frozen.
Gir: You gotta put it in warm water.
Trog: You gotta put it in two days in advance.
Log: It’s just a-it’s a load of shit.
They-they tell you to
do one thing, but the-their way—there’s
a universal way to unfreeze it and they
always tell you otherwise.
[Gir laughs]
Log: It’s shit, it’s just stupid.
Gir: Somethin’ about that just tickled me
so bad. Just Log
being mad that meat didn’t unfreeze and
calling it a load of shit [laughs].
Log: Yeah, they always tell you to thaw it
out in the
fridge, but thawin’ it out in the fridge
takes so long. It takes too long.
Trog: Yeah, I hate thawing food, that shit’s
sucks.
Log: Like whatever. Just take it out and just
put it on the
counter four hours before, and then it’s
good.
Gir: No, like if you get something—
Log: But I try to play by the rules—
Gir: Put it in warm-a warm bowl of water.
[Log sputters]
Gir: Not hot, but warm.
Log: I don’t have a good bowl for this.
Trog: Keep it in your mouth.
Gir: Do you have a sink?
Log: …I’m not gonna put it in the sink.
Gir: Oh my god, then don’t complain.
Log: I’m—[sighs] what do you think I’m
gonna do? Just put it
in-just at the bottom of the sink?
Gir: Yes! You plug the sink, set the meat
in there, put in
some water, and let it thaw!
Log: Gross.
Gir: Oh my god [laughs]! There’s nothin’
wrong with that!
Wayne: Nothin’ wrong with that! That’s
what you gotta do!
Log: I know my way around it, and I come through
at the end.
[Gir laughs]
Baaulp: I think we’re—I-we’re talking
about defrosting meat
now, I-I-this shit’s over, this shit’s
over!
Trog: Yeah, I think maybe it’s—I think
it’s time to fucking
mercy kill this goddamn podcast already.
[Wayne laughs]
Log: Whatever. You-make your-make your decision.
Wayne: Have we talked about, uh-I just got
this new fruit
wash.
Trog: Yeah.
Log: Come on, man.
Wayne: I spray the fruit and it gets all the
pesticides off.
I… I’ve been separating the darks from
the brights in my washer.
Gir, muttering: Nobody does that anymore.
Trog: Let’s do an outro where we each say
one word at a
time.
Wayne: Let’s go me, Gir, Trog, Log, Baaulp.
Okay? Alright.
Wayne: Thanks.
Gir, simultaneously: Bye.
[A pause of silence]
[Everyone laughs]
Gir: [Unintelligible]
Trog: Ah shit, that’s good, but we can’t-we
have to-we have
to do our plugs.
Wayne: That was good, but, yeah, let’s do
the plugs and then
we’ll do this. Okay, so anyways, y’know,
it’s been three months and the question,
it never stops arising, we don’t know where
to begin these podcasts, but we
always know how to end ‘em. This uh, if
you want to ask us a question for the
next Where Do We Begin podcast, you can either
join the WayneRadioTV Discord,
that’s discord.gg/wayneradiotv, I believe
we have that link now, um, the uh, or
you can email us at wheredowebeginqa@gmail.com
Uh, and we will take your question
and we might read it. There’s a lot of them
these days, but—
Baaulp: Yeah. And we pick the best, most interesting
ones.
Trog: Yeah.
Wayne: Mhmm. Like best-by date questions.
Trog: It’s a fuckin’ brown bag.
Wayne: Uh, if you wanna see more of what we’re
doing outside
of the podcast, the uh, we have an entire
Twitch Team. You can find me twitch.tv/wayneradiotv,
the uh, that’s where a lot of the bigger
productions go on we talked about,
like the AI-dventure Call stream and the-the
gorilla stream.
Trog: [Crosstalk] Great gorilla stream.
Wayne: But everybody doin’ somethin’!
Gir, what’re you doing
these days?
Gir: Uh, everywhere you can find me just by
searching MasterGir.
Twitch, Twitter, YouTube, like all of it.
Baaulp: Same thing for me, except it’s Baaulp,
B-A-A-U-L-P,
I just put out a new video last week, the
second episode of my talk show. Uh, maybe
I’ll get a real talk show one day, but until
then I have make on in my living
room. Uh, yeah, I also have started streaming
on Twitch pretty regularly,
Tuesdays through Fridays, and uh, yeah, more
content, follow me on social media
for weird funny stuff.
Trog: I have a Twitch channel as well, uh,
it is
twitch.tv/Tr0g because Trog was already taken,
so I-I had to do a zero. Maybe
someday I can get the URL.
Wayne: It’s a damn shame. Give Trog his
name!
Trog: Yeah I don’t know, I don’t know
how many viewers or
subscribers I need to steal somebody else’s
name, but let’s try to get me there.
Wayne: Maybe I can get enough to do it for
you, like to get
it [laughs].
Trog: And then I’m also on Twitter, and
that’s Trogort,
T-R-O-G-O-R-T, it’s like a little palindrome.
Um, yeah, I-I stream, we all
stream, everybody streams nowadays. Sometimes
video games, sometimes crosswords.
Wayne: I think it’s twitch.tv/team—is
it-it’s either team or
teams--/wrtv, you can see the entirety of
the RadioTVSolutions team. All nine
of us, including Moupi.
Trog: [Crosstalk] It is, yes.
Wayne: Uh, but anyways, how about we do our
little thing?
Trog: [Crosstalk] What about Log? Log didn’t
get to go, bitch.
Gir: [Crosstalk] Yeah, [unintelligible] Log,
You do that every time!
Wayne: Oh wait, fuck! [Screams]
Log: Observe Logmore on Twitch and LogBlaster
on Twitter! There are many mysteries to be
found! One way or another you’ll find out
about Gather Ye Power and how to reach it,
it’s pretty easy to get to it. You can
figure it out.
Trog: Wow, great plug.
Log: Use your hints. You can—There’s-there’s
multiple paths
you can take that come to this ending.
Wayne: Type promocode GatherYePower into Google.
Trog: Go to Kellogg’s.com and start from
there.
Gir: To get an exclusive—
Wayne: Get an exclusive coupon to read Gather
Ye Power for
free.
Gir: NFL.com, it’s cool. Check it out.
Wayne: Alright.
Gir: Guys.
Wayne: Thanks.
Trog: For.
Log: Party.
Baaulp: Time.
Wayne: It.
Gir: What?
Trog: [Laughs] Yeah.
Log: It [laughs].
Gir: Oh, you said ‘it’? All I heard on
my end was, “Eh.” …Alright,
say-say it again. Say it.
Wayne: Okay. So it was-it was, “Thanks guys
for the party
time?” It was, “Thanks guys for party
time,” It—
Gir: Was.
Trog: Never.
Log: Party.
Baaulp: Time.
[Gir laughs]
Trog: [Laughs] Maybe improv games are fun.
Wayne: However.
Gir: Alright. However, uh, say you have to
say-you have to
start it again ‘cause—
Wayne: However.
Gir: We.
Trog: Haven’t.
Log: Partied.
Baaulp, laughing: Time.
Log: I did past tense there, Baaulp.
Trog: Not grammatically correct.
Log: I did past tense there.
Baaulp: Times? Timed?
[Log, Trog, and Wayne laugh]
Gir: Will.
Wayne: Scream.
Gir: Loud.
Log: You did it backwards now.
[Wayne laughs]
Trog: Asparagus.
Log: Sautéed.
Gir, weakly: Time.
Log: [Laughs] Time. This sucks-this sucks
man, let’s go.